<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Features</title>
  <icon>https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/34086/verge-fv.png</icon>
  <updated>2015-08-05T10:09:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.theverge.com/rss/group/features/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/label/features" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-05T10:09:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-05T10:09:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>The New Devil’s Dictionary</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gOtRC4svRehxkU0WmPTKQtr8ZAI=/137x0:1576x959/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46901884/dictionaryhed.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;249 words for the end of the world&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/a/new-devils-dictionary"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/a/new-devils-dictionary</id>
    <author>
      <name>T.C. Sottek</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-04T15:00:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-04T15:00:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>How baseball’s tech team built the future of television</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tziGKjeIYCq2iv4gVJY4YHO_A4c=/0x0:720x480/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46895488/mlb-dot-com-8918_720.0.0.png" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;It was the first week of April, 2015, and New York’s Chelsea Market, typically packed with hordes of noisy tourists, was quiet. It was close to midnight, but five stories above, things were tense. The building is a former cookie factory, and the outlines of ovens still scar the brick walls. In their place, a vast array of screens are now mounted, each tuned to a live video feed. Joe Inzerillo and his team had their eyes glued to the glass, hard at work trying to wrangle the internet into doing something it was not built for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="BAM Cropped Cover Fade" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TyQueY1j4iqdGEr810NMyW0M7GY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3932290/mlb-dot-com-8918__3_.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The changeup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How baseball’s tech team built the future of television&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By Ben Popper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was the first&lt;/strong&gt; week of April, 2015, and New York’s Chelsea Market, typically packed with hordes of noisy tourists, was quiet. It was close to midnight, but five stories above, things were tense. The building is a former cookie factory, and the outlines of ovens still scar the brick walls. In their place, a vast array of screens are now mounted, each tuned to a live video feed. Joe Inzerillo and his team had their eyes glued to the glass, hard at work trying to wrangle the internet into doing something it was not built for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of HBO Now was just a few days away, but the product wasn’t finished. With both HBO and Apple promoting it heavily, the team had no idea how many people might tune in that first day. "The stakes were high," says Inzerillo. "It was not lost on anybody here how important this was for our company, but also for this industry. Because if HBO Now had come out and face planted, there would be a lot of naysayers who turned around and said, ‘See, this is why the adults need to handle television.’"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"Game of Thrones is our World Cup." &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six months earlier, HBO had announced it was cutting the cord, finally offering consumers access to their programming without signing up for cable or satellite television. But the in-house streaming service it had previously built, HBO Go, had experienced high-profile outages during the season four finale of &lt;i&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/i&gt; and the premiere of &lt;i&gt;True Detective&lt;/i&gt;. HBO Now was set to launch alongside the newest season of &lt;i&gt;GoT&lt;/i&gt;, and it had to be perfect. "&lt;i&gt;Game of Thrones &lt;/i&gt;is our World Cup,"&amp;nbsp;says Bernadette Aulestia, who runs HBO’s digital distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so HBO went to the company that set new records for online streaming during the 2014 World Cup, a strange tech startup hidden inside of a sports league, Major League Baseball Advanced Media, or BAM for short. BAM began as the in-house IT department for the league’s 30 teams, a small handful of employees originally tasked with building websites for teams and clubs. But over the last 15 years, BAM has emerged as the most talented and reliable name in streaming video, a skill set suddenly in very high demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAM competes for clients with streaming tech companies like NeuLion and Imagine Communications, as well as big telecommunication outfits like Verizon. But, says Dan Rayburn, a streaming industry analyst, "there really isn’t anybody who does the true end-to-end solution like MLB does, especially at scale, out in the market."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Their technical chops are the best, bar none," he adds. "They set the standard."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"The internet, as a technology, was never designed to do something like this."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HBO didn’t give BAM much time. "It was a full-on sprint for the three and half months that we had," says Inzerillo. As the clock ticked down, the crew from BAM ran through countless disaster scenarios. "What people forget is that the internet, as a technology, was never designed to do something like this — deliver flawless video simultaneously to millions of people." Inzerillo explains. "I liken it to trying to live on Mercury. The planet is completely inhospitable. Every day all you’re doing is [fighting] a battle for survival in a place that really does not want you. Streaming video on the internet is sort of like that."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 12th, a pair of fire-breathing dragons unleashed their fury across the internet — the &lt;i&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/i&gt; season five premiere, as well as the launch of HBO Now, were flawless. Today, BAM cemented its status as one of the most important players at the intersection of sports, media, and technology, announcing that it will be powering the mobile, web, and television offerings from the National Hockey League. It’s the first time BAM has been fully embraced by another major league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"When you have HBO going &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2012/11/12/3633984/future-of-tv-over-the-top"&gt;over the top&lt;/a&gt; and Bob Iger’s talking about ESPN going over the top, Viacom’s networks are being kicked off cable, we had a real gut check," says John Collins, the NHL’s chief operating officer. "BAM can help us dictate what happens to our content in a time when this media landscape is going through a lot of change."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the deal with HBO, BAM will power the league’s streaming services. But the deal goes even further — BAM will be a rights holder of NHL content they can package and sell to an online audience. "It’s groundbreaking to have two leagues doing a rights deal," says Collins. BAM recently forged a similar arrangement with the PGA. The new approach moves BAM beyond just a white label service provider, putting them in position to become an ESPN of the internet age, competing against the likes of Netflix, Hulu, and Amazon with the one thing all those services lack: live sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s just one catch. To make it all work, BAM has to grow beyond baseball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Announcement Image" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Jv98YM7Jk9PpLYy--yt797P_OI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3940924/mlb-nhl-deal-0122.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The announcement of BAM's partnership with the NHL. From left to right: NHL Chief Operating Officer John Collins, NHL Commissioner Gary Bettman, MLB Commissioner Rob Manfred, MLB President, Business, Bob Bowman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In late July,&lt;/strong&gt; I met Bob Bowman, BAM’s CEO, in the company’s office above Chelsea Market. We sat in a small conference room past a wall of trophies and a social media center blasting out baseball highlights across Twitter, Snapchat, Facebook, and YouTube. Bowman has CEO-caliber hair, swept up and to the right, in a dignified grey; he dresses in banker casual — khakis, boat shoes, and collared shirt unbuttoned at the top. On the whiteboard behind him, scrawled in black marker, was a warning: "INVESTORS GET FED! PIGS GET SLAUGHTERED."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bowman&amp;nbsp;is a man with 31 bosses and a client base that both uses and competes with MLB’s technical abilities. He has to navigate between traditional broadcasters, cable companies, and fans who want their game on any screen with an internet connection. He has perfected the art of partnerships that hinge on give and take. When I ask him the significance of the quote, he says it’s a reminder not to build your own business at the expense of people who pay you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"INVESTORS GET FED! PIGS GET SLAUGHTERED!"&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, BAM was a name known only to industry insiders, a sharpshooter organization called in to make sure the big game or series premiere streamed without fail. Over time, it forged long-term deals with clients like WWE and Sony Playstation’s Vue network. Now it’s moving from powering the platform to co-owning the content as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s increasingly clear that to really capture the opportunity in front of it, BAM needs to become more independent. BAM doesn’t run like a startup — it doesn’t have equity to share with employees, causing it to lose out on talented engineers and developers that want upside beyond a salary. It also can’t easily raise outside capital to compete against rising competitors like Twitch or Ooyala while it’s still a central part of baseball’s day-to-day operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of spinning BAM out to create a new company has been floated for years, but in the last few months it has hardened into a certainty. Today’s announcement that&amp;nbsp;the NHL will invest in this new venture makes it a fact. Lawyers and bankers are finalizing the details, and Bowman is in active discussions with other potential investors, poised to run a new company with a valuation north of $5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"As everyone thinks about going over the top, about building out a global business, we are looking for a partner to help us double or triple this business," says Bowman. "Things have been going fine, but to not move on this now, we lose the opportunity to get really, really big."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="BAM Office 1" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_Ld5JGAnvk31_pWAzgbIqYa0LKk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3934286/mlb-dot-com-8770.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When baseball’s then commissioner,&lt;/strong&gt; Bud Selig, created BAM back in 2000, he had relatively modest goals in mind. The unit would be in charge of creating websites for each of the teams and consolidating MLB’s digital rights. By pooling resources, he would prevent the bigger teams from outpacing their smaller market rivals. And to keep the division honest and efficient, BAM would operate as its own company. The teams agreed to contribute a combined $120 million to the venture, $1 million each over the first four years, with each taking an equal ownership stake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It was a painful lesson. From then on, BAM would build its own tech&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group they assembled wasn’t a Silicon Valley dream team, more like tech’s version of Bad News Bears: a minor league beat writer, a former state treasurer, and assorted AV nerds from around the league. This was the height of the dot-com boom, and excitement about the internet was at an all-time high. Right out of the gate, BAM decided to pay a fancy consulting firm a huge chunk of its annual budget to help it create the MLB.com website. Unfortunately the website barely worked. BAM had to scrap it and start from scratch. It was a painful lesson. From then on, BAM would build its own tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2001, Ichiro Suzuki came over from Japan to play for the Seattle Mariners. Already an icon in his home country, he now had a full-time press corps of several dozen Japanese reporters covering his every move. BAM decided to experiment with streaming live audio of his games, giving his fanatical followers a way to keep up in real time. The company spent several million dollars building and advertising the product. "I don’t think we ever got to 1,000 subscribers," says Bowman with a chuckle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the middle of 2002, heavy expenditures on these early projects had left the company strapped for cash. But when it consolidated the league’s digital rights, the MLB also gave BAM control over ticketing. BAM turned those rights into leverage. It made TicketMaster an offer: partner with us or you don’t sell baseball. The company gave BAM a $10 million advance, which it used to cover payroll as it pushed forward with its next big bet: video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The first video stream "looked more like a flip book."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 26th of 2002, BAM produced an online broadcast of a game between the Texas Rangers and New York Yankees. This was well before high-speed internet was ubiquitous and three years before the launch of YouTube. The game streamed to around 30,000 fans at a now glacial 280 kilobits per second. "The technology existed to do it, but of course, that doesn’t mean it was good," says Bowman. The first video stream "looked more like a flip book."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, fans responded to the new offering and BAM kept experimenting. Two weeks later, it launched the first paid streaming video product, a pennant race package of nine games with postseason implications. Later that fall, it sold a $19.95 postseason package. MLB.tv launched alongside spring training in 2003, offering a full season package for $79.95. In the first year, over 100,000 customers signed up. The new revenue stabilized BAM’s finances; it only ended up taking $77 million of funding from the team owners before it began paying them a dividend out of its profits. And the unique challenge of live streaming baseball started to shape BAM into the industry powerhouse it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="BAM Office 2" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NfddZOx94s4ajRgH8x4BBrncq7w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3934290/mlb-dot-com-8731.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching sports online has&lt;/strong&gt; always had one major complication: regional blackouts prevent you from streaming a game in the same territory as a television broadcaster who owns local rights. That meant BAM had to figure out where a customer was and whether or not they could legally watch the stream. In fact, BAM’s very first post-season package wasn’t even broadcast live in the United States or Japan. Fox owned the national broadcast rights to the pennant race, so BAM’s first big broadcast took place in Europe. From the beginning, BAM had to perfect live video streaming on a global scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Before anyone else was even thinking about these issues, BAM figured out compression, geofencing, and multi-application delivery at scale," says Rick Heitzman, a venture capitalist who has worked with BAM over the years. "Like many pioneers, they took their fair share of arrows, but have emerged as the leading digital platform." Bowman puts it a little differently. "We made all the same mistakes everyone else makes," he says. "We just had the advantage of making them first."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;"Before anyone else was even thinking about these issues, BAM figured out compression, geofencing, and multi-application delivery at scale."&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take syncing between devices. This is a great feature to have with a service like HBO Now, but with a baseball game, it’s absolutely critical. The last thing you want is a fan watching on their PC, pausing to head to the bathroom, pulling the game up on a phone, and suddenly it’s an inning later and the score has changed. BAM learned to do this with each game, and even with the stats a fan can pull up alongside the video for a deeper dive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inzerillo joined BAM&amp;nbsp;in 2003 and began work on what would become MLB.tv. He had started his career as a cameraman with the White Sox, moved on to direct video operations for the league, and then ran the tech department at Chicago’s newly created United Center. In 2000, he left baseball to work at a startup that was developing digital television. When the dot-com boom went bust, he fell back in with his old company, and brought along a wealth of knowledge about the intersection of TV and the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The thing about broadcast television is, today people probably think of it as stodgy old engineers with big beer bellies and a pocket protector," says Inzerillo. "But the truth is that there are a lot of things about the way they do it, the technology and the philosophy, that make it incredibly stable and scalable." Inzerillo set out to fuse those two worlds, creating a platform with the agility of a web startup and the reliability of a broadcast network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="BAM office 5" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nowYW7uVwkCegcd4t31k99dsP7o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3934506/mlb-dot-com-8859.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAM’s early entrance to the world of streaming video gave it a big advantage in developing technology, but it also gave the group a head start at the process of deploying infrastructure. Great web streaming requires "points of presence" spread across the globe near population centers. For 15 years, BAM has been building out data centers and high-speed fiber connections, forging intimate relationships with the companies that control the guts of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That head start gives BAM a massive advantage in both speed and cost. "We looked at what it would take to build in-house, and compared that to what BAM could deliver," said George Barrios, WWE's chief strategy and financial officer. "In the end it made a lot more sense to let them bring their technology expertise to bear, and focus on what we do best, which is creating great content and connecting with wrestling fans."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When HBO originally set out to create HBO Now, the project was &lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3044284/bring-it-on"&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; expected to take three years and cost $900 million. BAM turned the same project around in three and half months for less than $50 million. "We see a lot of things that are repeatable," says Kenny Gersh, the head of business development, who helped BAM close deals with ESPN, Sony, and the NHL. "We applied the learnings from MLB.tv to WWE, and we applied the learnings from WWE to HBO."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;By the time the iPhone rolled out in 2007, BAM was ready&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as it was early to video, BAM made a smart bet on mobile starting in 2005. That year, it built the MLB.com mobile site, which served up news and scores, and negotiated agreements with the four major US carriers to prominently feature a link to the site. A year later it launched its first mobile app, "MLB.com Gameday," across Verizon, AT&amp;T, and Sprint. The application included a scoreboard, Gameday pitch by pitch, and Live Gameday Audio — advanced features considering smartphone capabilities at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time the iPhone rolled out in 2007, BAM was ready. MLB was onstage for the unveiling of the App Store, the beginning of a deep relationship with Apple that would see it grace the stage at the launch of the iPad and Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it’s not just Apple that trusts BAM. Behind a locked door in its New York City headquarters, the company has a gadget geek’s fantasy trove: the latest smartphones, tablets, and consoles, all being tested months before they are publicly released. "On the iPhone, Roku, Playstation 3, Xbox 360, Apple TV, our infrastructure was always the first live streaming technology on those devices," says Matthew Gould, BAM’s head of communications. "Now people come to us to ensure that when their hardware is released, there won’t be any issues."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="BAM office 4" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CvWla2m9_-89q2UFoK6YGwnxyfA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3934304/mlb-dot-com-9158.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s easy to get&lt;/strong&gt; lost wandering through BAM’s headquarters. Hallways loop back on themselves and there are half floors wedged in between whole ones. Bobble heads and figurines line the partitions between desks; entire walls are crammed floor to ceiling with monitors where color codes flash onscreen: green for live, yellow for standby, red as a warning about a problem. Young men and women stand, chatting, never turning their gaze from the live feeds, a position known around the office as "eye to the glass."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;BAM has become a weird tech octopus&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Gould leads me on a tour, I realize what a weird tech octopus BAM has become; a unique mix of startup and IT department. The core competency and biggest revenue stream is technology for streaming living video. But it still builds and maintains websites for most MLB teams, created and manages the system that sells the league’s tickets, and constructs its mobile apps and games. Hell, BAM even powers instant replay for the league. On game day, an umpire comes and sits in a windowless room above Chelsea Market to review footage, calling whether a runner was safe at the plate or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest expression of this boundless initiative is Statcast, a big data approach to sports that only a major league nerd could love. High-speed cameras and radar installed in every stadium capture the game in three dimensions and allow for real-time tracking and tabulation of each motion a player makes on the field. Fans watching an amazing replay of a diving catch can learn exactly how fast that outfielder’s first step was, if he broke in the right direction, and how that compares to his historical average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://www.theverge.com/videos/iframe?id=75878" frameborder="0" seamless="true" marginwidth="0" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true" name="75878-chorus-video-iframe"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A promotional video explaining the technology behind MLB’s Statcast system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"My dad and I would go to Yankees games, and there would always be these arguments around Bernie Williams, how good an outfielder he was," explains Gregg Klayman, who runs product development and content strategy. "My dad, right or wrong, he would always say, Bernie breaks the wrong way, his first step is really slow, but he makes all these great catches, diving to the turf or bouncing off the wall. If he made the right step, it would have been easy."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"Was he a good player or just a very gifted athlete? ...Now I could know for sure."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then it was one of those friendly fan debates that would never get resolved. Today Klayman could simply call up the play on his smartphone and ask Statcast for the answer. "Was he a good player or just a very gifted athlete? Back then we had our opinions. Now I could know for sure."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every attempt at a new tech project is a success. When 2K, the publisher of licensed baseball games on the Xbox, decided against publishing a new title for 2015, BAM stepped in and created an entire console game from scratch in a year and a half. The result earned withering reviews, perhaps no surprise given that a team of a few dozen was tasked with a job usually done by hundreds of more experienced professionals over a much longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If BAM can pull off its plan to spin out as a stand-alone tech company, it could step away from such projects and focus on its core capabilities. "All the things that are related to baseball that aren’t streaming would stay behind at MLB," says Bowman. Instead of the utility infielder juggling a dozen different jobs, BAM Tech would focus solely on the streaming business, trying to stake a major claim in the rapidly shifting media market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="BAM Basketball" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0vgQSeaKgc34apE4XmaEOudnWIw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3934312/mlb-dot-com-8772.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few weeks ago,&lt;/strong&gt; Bowman sat down in a small studio at BAM’s headquarters to record a conversation with Rich Greenfield, an investment analyst and consigliere who works at the collision of media, technology, and television. Greenfield had recently helped guide the partnership between Vice and AMC, and was lobbing Bowman questions as an audience of bankers, venture capitalists, and potential investors tuned in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAM has been flirting with the idea of a spinoff since 2005, when it made the rounds with investors and bankers. But its revenue at the time was under $250 million, and streaming video was still far from mainstream. A decade later, BAM is on pace to earn $900 million, and says it’s been turning a steady profit. Add in a roster of high-profile clients and a massive media shift from pay TV to online streaming, and suddenly it seems silly not to look beyond baseball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Suddenly it seems silly not to look beyond baseball&lt;q&gt;&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NHL is the first public investor in BAM tech, but it's also talking with partners like HBO’s parent, Time Warner, and ESPN’s overlord, Disney, who could help sharpen its skills at producing and distributing original content. "While sports is often a leader in new forms of distribution, from VHS to DVD to streaming, the long tail here is entertainment," Bowman says. "And not just the standard formats. We want to be flexible enough to create new content that is specifically over the top."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bowman has some wild ideas for how BAM’s expertise could be tapped to create new genres. "Every night in clubs around the country, people are telling hundreds of jokes. Some of those are duds, but some are really funny." The BAM team already has experience ingesting petabytes of live footage from dozens of games and quickly cutting together highlights. "What if we could do that for comedy?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAM has already taken a step toward creating its own content by buying production and distribution rights for digital content from the PGA and NHL. Just as cable and ESPN provided a home for sporting events that didn’t match the business model of broadcast television, BAM is bundling sports to sell a la carte on the internet, creating a new opportunity, and perhaps a way forward as pay TV slowly dwindles. "The media space has always been built on over time, the platforms taking more control of content. It was true on cable with ESPN, and in streaming with Netflix. So it’s natural," says Greenfield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;BAM is bundling sports to sell a la carte on the internet, creating a new opportunity&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of helping to produce and perhaps even create new content is intriguing, but also risky. BAM would find itself competing directly with its own clients, like ESPN and HBO. A big part of the company’s success was its ability to work with companies and leagues traditionally viewed as competitors. "Media companies are not good at tech and really struggle with large scale," says Greenfield. "They don’t trust companies like Google or Amazon, who want to displace them. BAM is seen as friendly." If it spins out and starts making its own shows, that dynamic may change. And while it’s a world class technology company, so far it has little track record in creating original content outside baseball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As consumers cut the cord on cable, BAM and its clientele are navigating treacherous waters. "It’s more complex than ever for media companies," says Bowman. "You need to honor your existing partners, your existing contracts, while also figuring out new ways to reach fans who live beyond the traditional formats." So far BAM has managed to bridge the gap between television and the internet. And Bowman is bullish on the future. "The fact that you can now deliver games on demand 24/7 to 4 billion devices around the globe, you couldn’t write heaven for a sports fan better than that."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;

&lt;div class="chorus-snippet m-fishtank no-responsive-video"&gt;&lt;chorus-ad data-ad-slot="athena_features"&gt;&lt;/chorus-ad&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;div id="credit"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;* *&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photography by &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://alexwelshphoto.com/"&gt;Sean O'Kane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited by &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/users/dieterbohn"&gt;Dieter Bohn&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mvzelenks"&gt;Michael Zelenko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/4/9090897/mlb-bam-live-streaming-internet-tv-nhl-hbo-now-espn"/>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="video/mp4" href="http://www.theverge.com/rss/redirect.mp4?url=http://ak.c.ooyala.com/RmOWNvdjoiJqod-iMfY3CLCkps9ZisyE/DOcJ-FxaFrRg4gtDEwOjFpaDowODE7jj"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/4/9090897/mlb-bam-live-streaming-internet-tv-nhl-hbo-now-espn</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ben Popper</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-07-29T08:00:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-29T08:00:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>The story of Windows 10 from inside Microsoft</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ixwvPvo7PaQnZAQz4MltvNndE6g=/0x0:2039x1359/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46857296/verge-2015-07-21_12-27-18.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;Windows 10 has a lot to live up to. Microsoft has made a lot of promises about it. And oddly enough, we’ve heard most of them before, with Windows 8. Both were designed to acknowledge and embrace mobile and mobile apps, work well on touchscreens as well as laptops, and form the basis of a new phone platform. But there’s a big difference between them: Windows 10 actually does all those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Windows 10" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mw-0YJcXgskhSjRysC9vPyHQqDM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3913184/VLS_7466.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The story of Windows 10 from inside Microsoft&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The company's latest trick: listening to its users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By Tom Warren&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows 10 has a lot to live up to&lt;/strong&gt;. Microsoft has made a lot of promises about it. And oddly enough, we’ve heard most of them before, with Windows 8. Both were designed to acknowledge and embrace mobile and mobile apps, work well on touchscreens as well as laptops, and form the basis of a new phone platform. But there’s a big difference between them: Windows 10 actually does all those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years ago, tablets like the iPad looked like they might be a serious threat to Windows. In response, Steve Ballmer, Steven Sinofsky, and the rest of Microsoft took a big bet on a forward-thinking interface that asked its users to forget their old point-and-click ways and embrace a tiled future. Windows 8 and Windows Phone 8 were related pieces in a bold strategy to move the company into a future of touchscreens and connected apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That strategy flopped. Users roundly rejected the confusing new version of Windows, and without them, developers balked. But the iPad hasn’t killed off laptops, and consumers haven’t shown a big interest in touchscreen PCs yet. Another version, 8.1, attempted to stem the bleeding, but it was too late. The market had spoken. Like Vista before it and Windows ME before that, Windows 8 was the version of Windows you skipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside style="padding-left: 3rem; padding-bottom: 1rem; padding-top: 2rem;" class="float-right"&gt; &lt;q&gt;Read our full &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/28/9045331/microsoft-windows-10-review"&gt;Windows 10 review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/q&gt; &lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, a new leadership team for Windows under CEO Satya Nadella and executive vice president Terry Myerson are trying it all again. But this time around, the goal is much more ambitious: if they succeed, Windows 10 will be the final iteration of Windows: The one that will be updated like a service, continuously, in perpetuity. The one that finally makes good on all the promises of a synergistic ecosystem of like-minded devices designed to work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a series of exclusive interviews with &lt;i&gt;The Verge&lt;/i&gt;, the team behind Windows 10 revealed how they’re doing it, why they think it will succeed, and what they’re working on next. This is the story of Windows 10 from inside Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZwvMA6QFD5e1h2tYI6Uvn_qvXSw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3916086/verge-2015-07-21_10-01-08.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;Terry Myerson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Developing in the open&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terry Myerson never imagined he’d last at Microsoft. "I thought I was going to stay here a couple of weeks, but found that I really loved the people."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s now 18 years since Myerson sold his small company to Microsoft, during which time he worked on Exchange, Windows Mobile, and Windows Phone. Now, he’s sitting in front of me as the head of Windows, just days before the software maker launches Windows 10. It’s been two years since Myerson was promoted to the top job, and the release is important to him and the company.  Microsoft needs customers to love and want Windows enough to upgrade to it, thereby creating a massive install base to attract developers. The pressure is on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myerson is confident without being arrogant — he’s more than happy to tease me about my MacBook. His forthright manner is mirrored in how he chose to release Windows 10: out in the open, bugs and all, even before the company had finished thinking through what it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;
&lt;div class="blue"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"You're putting it out there when it's not done."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft now solicits feedback directly from users in a very public way: over the past nine months, the company has been testing Windows 10 with 5 million "Windows Insiders." Anyone can sign up to test, and the results of Microsoft’s work will go on display today as Windows 10 launches to millions of people around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It has sometimes been daunting," says Myerson. "You're putting it out there when it's not done, then you're getting all kinds of feedback and stuff that you know is broken." That feedback has been constant and varied over the last nine months, and it will continue over the months and years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, "there was a lot of hand-wringing around what was that going to be like and were people going to form opinions too early," explains Gabe Aul, engineering general manager for Microsoft’s operating systems group. "I think we just decided to go for it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aul launched his Microsoft career in product support 23 years ago. He went on to help build Dr. Watson, a debugger that gathers error data when your PC crashes, into basically every product at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today Aul is the face of Microsoft’s Windows 10 testing. He receives Microsoft feedback, praise, and abuse on Twitter daily, but he remains perfectly cool. Even before we start our interview, I start moaning about some Windows 10 bugs I have, and he’s keen to listen, even emailing me a fix for a problem within seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He admits he’s "passionate about quality" after working in product support for years, and it’s clear he genuinely cares. While many will joke IT support is simply a help desk asking a user to reboot their PC, Microsoft has built a whole system to process the feedback it receives for Windows 10. It all gets collected in a database where Microsoft engineers can use tools to analyze it visually. If Cortana starts breaking in France, Microsoft will hear about it, and engineers can detect trends and issues based on pop-ups that appear for testers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;
&lt;div class="red"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"There was a lot of hand-wringing around what was that going to be like."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback doesn’t always come from within the operating system, though. The Continuum feature, which lets you switch between desktop and tablet modes in Windows 10, generated a wave of negative responses from  social media. That’s probably because Microsoft initially ripped out all of Windows 8’s good touch work, a move that surprised testers, before slowly building it back in. "The trash can icon — the feedback we got on that thing..." He cuts short to laugh because Windows Insiders (&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/2/23/8089387/microsoft-windows-10-new-icons"&gt;myself included&lt;/a&gt;) were really vocal in comments and online forums about the how ugly the first version was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, Windows customers reached out to Myerson directly, including one during the time when the Windows chief misspoke and the result was that everybody thought Windows 10 would be free. "There's this kid in Bangladesh who somehow got my email address, he runs pirated Windows," Myerson says. "It was a great dialogue. It was more for me a learning experience about how did he pirate Windows, and why did he pirate Windows." The conversation hasn’t changed Microsoft’s stance, though. Windows 10 still isn’t free for pirates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Xbox app Windows 10" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a__7LbDuityQh2r1QVJ7sLEzdto=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3912996/xbone1_2040.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;The new Xbox One app on Windows 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To handle feedback, the Windows build team hosts daily "flight ops" meetings to decide which prerelease versions of Windows 10 get released. A "flight commander" takes control of the team, for that day. "He has a red hat that says ‘phone’ on it, and he has a black hat that says ‘PC’ on it," Aul says. "When it’s time to talk about phone, he will take the PC hat off and put the phone hat on. That’s how we keep the room in check."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikevierling"&gt;@mikevierling&lt;/a&gt; It's real :-) &lt;a href="http://t.co/dwF9EJOQkQ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/dwF9EJOQkQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Gabriel Aul (@GabeAul) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GabeAul/status/601072291099860992"&gt;May 20, 2015&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also a red outfit hanging on the wall, a symbol of a time when one employee came to the ship room wearing embarrassing matching red shorts and a T-shirt (he’s an Ohio State supporter). It became a running joke. Now, if a Microsoft engineer enters the meeting with a bug that’s equally embarrassing, they have to wear something red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To continue with the red theme, Aul has a 3D-printed red button that’s become something of a Microsoft meme among Windows fans. Aul hits it when a build is ready to be released to the public. "It’s mostly ceremonial, but it actually does send a trigger to the flighting system," explains Aul. "The other thing it does, that most people don’t know, is it says something inappropriate in a Stephen Hawking voice because it’s got a voice synthesizer in there." Aul wouldn’t give me any examples, but quotes are sourced from the team or jokes about his tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s willingness to solicit user feedback on early versions is a big change from the past. During the days of Vista, Microsoft’s lawyers ended up at my doorstep because I dared to write about prerelease versions of Windows. And while Windows 8 had a few public previews, it was largely developed with little consideration to feedback. Windows 8 shipped despite user concerns about fullscreen apps and a lack of attention to keyboard and mouse users. Microsoft’s management seemed to spend more time explaining every new feature in sprawling, technical blog posts instead of understanding why users hated the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myerson has a different philosophy: "It isn't one guy comes down from a mountain with a tablet [saying] what the right product is," he explains. "We just believe the customer feedback shaping the product is how we're going to build clarity and confidence that we have a great product."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9tr_uxTeLUJ6HNWayv7cGah2xcI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3916090/verge-2015-07-21_11-53-26.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;Joe Belfiore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;From apps to phones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft may have been confident about Windows 8, but the ambitions to push touch computing didn’t work out. Microsoft has been forced to admit several times that it’s aware customer satisfaction rates for mouse and keyboard users are low. Microsoft’s new Start menu isn’t as domineering, it’s just designed to get them to move to Windows 10. "Our strategic belief is, if we have a big audience of people… then developers will put apps in that store because there will be demand," explains Microsoft’s Joe Belfiore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;
&lt;div class="yellow"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"We now have all the devices lined up. I don't expect to see the platform change again."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belfiore looks after the customization of Windows for PCs, tablets, and phones. He spent years building Windows Phone, alongside Myerson. To many fans, he’s the face of Microsoft’s mobile efforts. Microsoft has been constantly resetting and rebuilding its Windows Phone OS. Windows Phone 7 users couldn’t upgrade to Windows Phone 8, and it took far too long for Windows Phone 8.1 to arrive with features that should have been there from the beginning. It’s knocked developer confidence, to say nothing of crippling its chances at gaining significant marketshare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of Windows 10’s big promise is that the same apps can run across PCs, tablets, phones, and even the Xbox One console. As a result, the next phones will have an expansive set of apps from Windows 10 to jumpstart the ecosystem. "We have one common operating system for all the device types that we are making," explains Belfiore. He’s also surprisingly blunt when he characterizes Windows Phone 7 and Windows Phone 8, products he was intimately involved in developing.  "We've had a couple of, sort of, practice runs with phone and PC," Belfiore says, before pivoting to the presumably brighter future with Windows 10, "We now have all the devices lined up. I don't expect to see the platform change again, in the same way it has before."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s encouraging to hear, but it doesn’t help Windows Phone right now. Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella revealed recently that the company is restructuring its phone business, scaling it back massively as part of a $7.6 billion write-off from the Nokia phone business acquisition. Around 7,800 jobs are being cut, and Microsoft is planning to make fewer models. "We are going to focus on a few great devices and the most notable being that premium consumer category," explains Myerson, adding, "The direction we will head is the premium-branded lineup." I push him on whether that’s a similar approach to Surface, and he claims "the goal is to have one Microsoft device family that plays this role in the Windows ecosystem." I’m not sure if that means a Surface Phone is in the cards, but it sure sounds like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first example of that one Microsoft device family will arrive later this year. "One's coming. Maybe two are coming, but at least one is coming," teases Myerson, as he hides an unreleased Lumia phone in his pocket. Microsoft is rumored to be working on two high-end devices that will include a new Continuum feature from Windows 10. Continuum on phones lets you use the phone as kind of a PC. You can connect up a keyboard, mouse, and monitor and start using Windows 10 apps. "I think it is the future of the phone," says Myerson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belfiore is equally bullish about Continuum, but the phone version of Windows 10 doesn’t ship until later this year. "The phone is significantly feature complete, but we'll continue to polish and tweak and iterate the things that still need to work," explains Belfiore. "We'll put features in right up near the end. But in general, the broad feature set is set."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZhOxUHIE9TqPBtum0gSFjiaaYlg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3916092/verge-2015-07-21_14-59-02.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;Phil Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Windows 10 and the Xbox One&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 10 is also coming to the Xbox in a big way. A new Xbox app for Windows 10 is a significant addition, and it’s one of the best built-in apps available right now. You can stream Xbox One games to a Windows 10 PC and use the Xbox controller, and you can chat freely from a PC to an Xbox One with or without a headset. It’s a great addition for Xbox gamers after a rough couple of years. Sales have been second to Sony’s PlayStation 4, but it feels like Microsoft is recovering from the original unveiling of the Xbox One two years ago. "The launch of Xbox One, it was from a brand and a customer pride standpoint… a tough time," says Phil Spencer, Microsoft’s head of Xbox. "A lot of the original ideas around Xbox One didn't meet the expectations that Xbox fans have of what we should do with our product."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spencer, who has worked on products like Encarta at Microsoft, has spent the last year or so getting the Xbox team re-centered on its fans and gaming. It’s an approach that Myerson says inspired the Windows Insider program. "Xbox had this passionate focus on their fans and engaging with their fans and listening to their fans," says Myerson. "Something that Phil Spencer just has at his core is his caring. He lives for those Xbox fans."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;
&lt;div class="green"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"We understand if you're going to go PC to Xbox, we need to get keyboard and mouse working."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spencer sees Windows 10 as a "massive opportunity" to bring Xbox Live and a single store to people. Today, the Xbox store is separate from the Windows store, but Microsoft is unifying them this fall. That doesn’t mean apps will be immediately available on the Xbox One, though. "Getting to one store where all the content is there will happen a little bit later," says Spencer, meaning we’ll be waiting until next year until we finally see Windows 10 apps on Xbox One. Microsoft’s store isn’t designed to kill off Steam, either. "Five years from now, I want Steam to be incredibly popular and successful. I look at the health of Steam as a harbinger of the health of Windows gaming."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is coming this year is a Windows 10 update for Xbox One that brings a refreshed UI, speed, and Microsoft’s Cortana digital assistant. "You can imagine scenarios of ‘Hey Cortana, what are most of my friends playing? What are most people watching?’" says Spencer. "The next step is being able to help you in-game, of really thinking about scenarios like ‘Hey Cortana, how do I get past this boss?’" Further out, Spencer says that streaming PC games to Xbox One is something he wants to enable. "We understand if you're going to go PC to Xbox, we need to get keyboard and mouse working completely so you could play those games. In terms of where we want to go with our platform, those are absolutely in the scope of things that we want to do."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9glrYRiLnJJlWSJbvpmZaiFNNvY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3916098/verge-2015-07-21_12-27-18.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;Terry Myerson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The last Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myerson and his team have shifted Windows 10 to a "&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/5/7/8568473/windows-10-last-version-of-windows"&gt;Windows as a service&lt;/a&gt;" model, meaning regular updates instead of a major release every few years. It doesn’t feel like Microsoft really knows exactly how this is going to play out, but the Windows 10 release marks a milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;
&lt;div class="blue"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company simply can’t afford to make the mistakes of Windows 8 again&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s not the kind of milestone we’re used to. Windows 10, even at release, is not done. Right now, it’s all about updates that fix issues and bugs. If you upgrade from Windows 7 and Windows 8 this week, then you’ll start to see those regular updates, and they’ll install automatically to keep everyone up to date. Myerson is confident in the quality of Windows 10. "We look at these quantitative metrics and we think the quality's great, and we're continuing to fix more," he says. "We're going to keep fixing. We're committed to listen and respond. Every day we're shipping out new updates with 30 more fixes."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That listening and responding sums up Windows 10. If there’s something wrong this time, then Myerson and his team will be listening. This can’t (and likely won’t) be another Windows 8 or Windows Vista mess for Microsoft. The company simply can’t afford to make those mistakes again. "Our goal is to roll out Windows 10 and build a base of millions of happy and engaged Windows 10 users," says Myerson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Happy and engaged" is one of those talking points you hear a lot from Microsoft. Myerson used it nine times in our hour together. But behind the PR-approved phrasing is a simple truth: it’s been a long time since Windows users have been either, and Microsoft needs to fix that. It’s as good a North Star as any, especially when your product development cycle is founded on taking user feedback seriously. If Microsoft can make people love Windows again, then the rest — developers and apps — is easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’ve learned anything from speaking to the team building Windows 10, it’s that Microsoft is taking user feedback very, very seriously. Everything Microsoft is making — from the Xbox to phones to HoloLens — is based on Windows 10. It’s not just the foundation of this operating system, it’s the future foundation of the company. Microsoft doesn’t have a Plan B for Windows, and it’s proud of the fact: "There's no one working on a Windows 11," Myerson says, "but there's a group of people working on some really cool updates to Windows 10." When Windows Insiders see those updates, you can be sure Microsoft will want to know exactly what they think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;div class="chorus-snippet m-fishtank no-responsive-video"&gt;&lt;chorus-ad data-ad-slot="athena_features"&gt;&lt;/chorus-ad&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="credit"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;* *&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photography by David Ryder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited by Dieter Bohn and Michael Zelenko&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/29/9060891/microsoft-windows-10-myerson-belfiore-aul-spencer-interview"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/29/9060891/microsoft-windows-10-myerson-belfiore-aul-spencer-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-07-28T13:00:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-28T13:00:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Why Grooveshark failed</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mr4BrmH32lRCUXv_qQ29AnVD44w=/0x120:2833x2009/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46849608/8028363238_7561171821_o.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;Sometime in early 2006, Josh Greenberg, a freshman at the University of Florida, began attending meetings at a school club for budding business types. The son of an electronics repairman, Greenberg was a model junior entrepreneur. In high school he’d run a small web design business; at 17, he’d incorporated it, printing his first run of business cards. Underage, he couldn’t legally serve on his company’s board of directors, so he appointed his grandfather as chairman. Now 19, Greenberg was looking to build something more concrete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having come of age in the dot-com era, Greenberg was invested in the myth of the dorm-room billionaire. In the late '90s, audacious entrepreneurs had built billion-dollar businesses in direct violation of copyright law, and they had flourished. One should move quickly, drop out of college, break the rules. Greenberg did all three, building a digital music platform that was years ahead of its time. Called Grooveshark, it helped sparked the music streaming revolution, and for a brief time in the late 2000s, it looked poised to eclipse iTunes, BitTorrent, and maybe even Spotify as the platform of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Grooveshark looked poised to eclipse iTunes, BitTorrent, and maybe even Spotify&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Greenberg’s ambition blinded him to a quiet but enormously important shift — after years of acrimonious opposition, the technologists and the rights holders were beginning to cooperate. Behind the scenes, the creative industries were recapturing their ability to protect the flow of information. This shift was subtle at first; even most of the pundits missed it. With time, though, it became clear that Grooveshark was on the wrong side of the trend, and that the service was doomed. Earlier this spring, it streamed its final song.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, last Sunday, Josh Greenberg was found dead in his home. The cause of death could not immediately be determined; it will be some time before a toxicology test provides the final answers. He had no history of illness, and his family said he had seemed upbeat about new ventures in the weeks before his death. Whatever the cause, his passing represents the end of an era — a bookend to a more radical chapter in the history of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Josh Greenberg" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4Ml93Wfs6Pj5fJxsj2cxcyFITHM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3892064/greenberg.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Image courtesy of Gavin Doran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2006, Greenberg didn’t even have a business plan. Instead, he simply showed up at the campus entrepreneurs’ club, prepared to offer his programming skills to anyone with a good idea. There he met another freshman, Sam Tarantino, who had a radical proposal — in the aftermath of Napster, he was going to get people to pay for music again. By combining Tarantino’s managerial ambitions with Greenberg’s technical skills, the two could make music piracy obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A more experienced business partnership might have chosen a less ambitious goal&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not immediately clear how this was to be accomplished; a more experienced business partnership might have chosen a less ambitious goal. But Greenberg and Tarantino were young and eager to swim in the deep end. Within a few months, they’d incorporated a company, Escape Media Group, and debuted the earliest version of Grooveshark: a limited-use file-sharing application that offered some basic social networking capability alongside the ability to pay for downloadable mp3 files. It failed. They pulled it, added some functionality, and relaunched Grooveshark in beta. That failed, too. This was the mid-2000s, the high days of Kazaa, LimeWire, and BitTorrent. It was hard to compete with free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2007, Grooveshark’s founders went back to the whiteboard. They were still college students, but now they had a couple years of experience and were learning to focus and think strategically. They realized their product was too complicated, and decided to focus on just one specific feature. Inspired by the success of YouTube, Greenberg and Tarantino reasoned that a next-generation shouldn’t sell mp3s at all. Instead, it should stream them, just as YouTube did with videos. And rather than selling files, they’d sell advertising, or, for premium users, even subscriptions. That way, they could subvert the pirates by abandoning the download model entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We thought of the main silos of content on the internet," &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110527220518/http://www.startupsopensourced.com/groovesharks-interview/"&gt;Greenberg would later say&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;"If you want photos, you go to Flickr or Google Images; if you want videos or shows, you go to YouTube or Hulu; but if you think music, there is no place to go to."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Grooveshark redesign" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/966Co94l_evKiRhCdBFzd0t3yqs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/2555716/gshark3.1318372153.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grooveshark streaming application launched in April of 2008 — several months ahead of Spotify. The service proved explosively popular from the outset. Users, especially younger users, loved on-demand music delivery, and Greenberg left school to focus on Grooveshark full time. But there was a problem: Grooveshark still relied on peer-to-peer infrastructure similar to Napster, Kazaa, and bitTorrent. In other words, although it functioned as a streaming service, it still sourced the music from its users’ file libraries. And to the record companies, that looked like copyright infringement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company struggled to make payroll&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without approval from the labels, Grooveshark struggled to attract venture capital. In its first five years of existence, the company raised just under a million dollars. In the same time, Spotify, with equity buy-in from the music majors, raised a hundred times as much. Even as Grooveshark grew to nearly 30 million registered user accounts, the company struggled to make payroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a technical perspective, of course, Grooveshark was excellent. The peer-to-peer architecture outsourced the distribution work to the users, and this decentralized approach allowed Greenberg, now the company’s CTO, to serve the world on a pauper’s budget. But, having dropped out of college, he was still working out of a low-rent office in Gainesville, Florida. The company, for all its popularity, was still run by kids. Without investment from venture capital, it couldn’t attract veteran managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt; &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Grooveshark Logo" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mUsoEpUObqgNf4RoeHhrsBB5FCw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3914006/4835606101_f046ef32db_q.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grooveshark tried to go legitimate. In 2009, It signed a contract with EMI, one of the world’s largest music companies, promising to pay out royalties for the songs that users streamed. But rather than saving the company, the deal revealed an embarrassing lack of professionalism: EMI would later complain that, over the course of three years, it was never once provided with an accurate account of what had actually been streamed. Eventually, EMI sued Grooveshark. So did every other major music company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A crackdown followed. Grooveshark applications were removed from the Apple App Store and Google Play, and booted from Facebook. The service began dropping users. In response, Grooveshark, under Greenberg’s technical direction, went back to the web, building a richly featured HTML5 application. This prevented the tech giants from blocking the service. But it also meant that, as the rest of the world was going mobile, Grooveshark was moving back to the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"I am like literally broke."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Spotify grew exponentially, stealing Grooveshark’s users. The Swedish service was especially popular among the desirable under-25 demographic; after a decade of free music, young people had started paying again. Piracy was going obsolete, just as Greenberg and Tarantino had always envisioned — only Grooveshark wasn’t responsible. By early 2012, the company’s active user base had been cut in half. In 2013, Tarantino told a reporter from &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/22/grooveshark-radio/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; he was "literally broke. I am like literally broke and am trying to lower my rent."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2014, the execution writ was signed. A federal judge determined that Grooveshark’s peer-to-peer streaming approach was a flagrant violation of copyright law. The undercapitalized company now owed the major labels enormous damages — damages it could never hope to pay. On April 30th, 2015, Grooveshark went dark. In a post to the company’s website, the Grooveshark team explained how they had given all they had — their patents, their websites, their copyrights — to the record companies as a belated kind of compensation. "We failed to secure licenses from rights holders for the vast amount of music on the service," they wrote on Grooveshark’s landing page. "That was wrong. We apologize. Without reservation."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Grooveshark cards" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9iF-rupfqBw95qMBg128UZd0Ue8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3913948/292543750_9a9bc37eaa_o.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/vrogy/292543750/in/photolist-rRn4L-9uXYmv-RZjcr-auFB62-7dsZrJ-4LfqBx-4Lfpwi-4HkL2u-PU2Vg-5uvwn7-dH4ZQf-NpAFg-6Tqipg-39W2Bt-Mu9m2-Mdj4m-6TqiiB-6Tuj8J-6Tuj3y-4LjD8q-9zU3hB-4LjCBb-6TtK9R-6hcNs9-6hcNjj-6hcNgS-6hcNdJ-6Tqide-rRn5A-rRn5i-7d6LqB-4LjCi3-aWBNkP-6h8C6n-MhrD1-NWJRG-rVCy8-5kDxyY-rRn4h-4JscNi-4JwqUf-4JscGH-aJE3c4-4Jscua-abZC26-ai6BBH-NrKzG-4zSTvE-tuthf-NrSu5" target="new"&gt;Image courtesy of Michael Vroegop/Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three months later, Josh Greenberg, the brains behind the world’s first on-demand music streaming service, was found dead in his home. He had spent the last nine years of his life — his entire adulthood — building a successful and popular service, only to watch it end in disgrace. The company he’d founded was ruined, and the promised billions never came. He was 28 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenberg was not a criminal; he was not even a profiteer. He had not, like Kim Dotcom, attempted to locate his business, or himself, outside of the United States. Nor, it should be said, was he a hero. He was not an Aaron Swartz or Edward Snowden, liberating privileged information from corrupt structures of governance. He was just a businessman. He was a young entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had violated the tenets of intellectual property law, of course, but there was precedent for that. Nullsoft’s Justin Frankel had coded Winamp without licensing the underlying mp3 technology; YouTube’s Steve Chen and Chad Hurley had looked the other way as users had uploaded thousands of infringing videos; Napster’s Shawn Fanning had acted as if the entire concept of copyright was obsolete. Greenberg resembled them. He was a scion of middle-class America; he’d attended a state school; he was young, and male, and comfortable with the internet’s culture of appropriation. The template was to move fast and to break things, and to let the lawyers figure out the repercussions once you’d earned your millions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;With a little luck, the company might have outmaneuvered Spotify&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Grooveshark had debuted in 2003, or maybe even 2005, he might have gotten away with it. Like a claim-jumper in the 19th century, Grooveshark could perhaps have emerged from the era of digital lawlessness with enough leverage to force the music companies to the negotiating table, and borrowed enough expertise from the venture capitalists to become a functional business. With a little luck, the company might have outmaneuvered Spotify, and Greenberg would have been a business icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if Grooveshark had failed in those days, Greenberg could have had a sunny future. He certainly wasn’t the first businessman to launch his career at a quasi-legal file-sharing service. Facebook’s Sean Parker had done so; so had Uber’s Travis Kalanick; so, even, had Spotify’s Daniel Ek. For internet executives of a certain generation, a failed stint in the peer-to-peer space was like an alternative to an MBA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But by the time Grooveshark actually debuted its streaming application, in 2008, the frontier had closed. Indeed, the most surprising thing about the service was that it lasted as long as it did. A mid-2000s peer-to-peer service was raffish, but still viable; a mid-2010s peer-to-peer service was sordid, possibly untouchable. Grooveshark was the last major operator in the space, outlasting Kazaa, LimeWire, and dozens more, and Greenberg’s long-time association with the company may have irreducibly stained his reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The legend of the rule-breaking dorm-room billionaire lives on&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift to the smartphone made the difference. Decisions made in the early days of personal computing had given users an enormous amount of freedom: to collaborate, to produce, to share files without oversight. In the mobile era, those decisions were being reversed. Users were no longer producers who were to be empowered, they were consumers from whom value was to be extracted. The smartphone (or tablet) of today feels less like a collaborative tool for communication and more like a sales kiosk. Unlike the Wild West days of the web, today a few tech giants — Facebook, Google, and Apple — determine which apps are permitted, and which are not. And they want to keep the media companies happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this profound change in the power structure of the internet, the legend of the rule-breaking dorm-room billionaire lives on. I wonder if it still has any basis in reality. It’s been almost 20 years since the first mp3s began circulating on college campuses; it’s been more than 10 since Mark Zuckerberg founded Facebook. Is it possible for the junior entrepreneur of today to do what Frankel (18), Fanning (18), Parker (19), and Zuckerberg (19) did? I doubt it. The rules are in place now; the upstart rebels are established players. There will still be young entrepreneurs of course, but they’ll have to settle for preapproved real estate in mobile computing’s digital mall. It’s time to retire the rule-breaker ethos. We don’t know why Greenberg died, but we do know why Grooveshark failed. There was no place for it in the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stephenwitt" target="new"&gt;Stephen Witt&lt;/a&gt; is the author of &lt;/em&gt;How Music Got Free: The End of an Industry, the Turn of the Century, and the Patient Zero of Piracy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br id="1438089303803"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/28/9054093/why-grooveshark-failed"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/28/9054093/why-grooveshark-failed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Witt </name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-07-22T10:43:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-22T10:43:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>A true crime tale of comic books, corruption, and a $9 million vanishing act</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KUwODIeROoepc88nyAjue77SCaE=/0x99:1982x1420/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46798856/New_Cover.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;You don't see an All Star Comics #3 every day. Published in 1940, it’s a milestone in what’s known as the Golden Age of comic books: the debut of the first bonafide superhero team, the Justice Society of America. There’s hardly a plot, only a meeting of some of DC’s biggest stars — Flash, Green Lantern, Hawkman — taking turns sharing tales as if they were telling ghost stories at a campfire. Spectre recounts a battle with a monster from the moon; Hawkman remembers a crisis on the island of Krakatoa. The masked vigilantes on the cover are a friendly lot, decades removed from the gritty realism that would come to dominate the industry later. The Flash wears a slightly over-sized long-sleeve shirt, emblazoned with a yellow lightning bolt. His face is as pleasant and plain as a dumpling, and on his head sits a helmet that brings to mind an overturned colander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Comic Book Cover" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b_bZCMCqLAhSLjaEqL2r5kjNdBw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3896126/New_Cover.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Comic Conman&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A true crime tale of comic books, corruption, and a $9 million vanishing act&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By Russell Brandom &amp; Colin Lecher | Illustrations by Jun Cen&lt;/h3&gt;
 &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;div class="firstcharacter"&gt;Y&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span&gt;ou don’t see an &lt;i&gt;All Star Comics&lt;/i&gt; #3 every day.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published in 1940, it’s a milestone in what’s known as the Golden Age of comic books: the debut of the first bonafide superhero team, the Justice Society of America. There’s hardly a plot, only a meeting of some of DC’s biggest stars — Flash, Green Lantern, Hawkman — taking turns sharing tales as if they were telling ghost stories at a campfire. Spectre recounts a battle with a monster from the moon; Hawkman remembers a crisis on the island of Krakatoa. The masked vigilantes on the cover are a friendly lot, decades removed from the gritty realism that would come to dominate the industry later. The Flash wears a slightly over-sized long-sleeve shirt, emblazoned with a yellow lightning bolt. His face is as pleasant and plain as a dumpling, and on his head sits a helmet that brings to mind an overturned colander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when an &lt;i&gt;All Star Comics &lt;/i&gt;#3 surfaced at Heritage Auctions’ first big sale of 2012, collectors took notice. The copy was off-white, its condition ranked at 8.5 out of 10 by the Certified Guaranty Company. CGC knew of only two higher-ranked &lt;i&gt;All Star&lt;/i&gt; #3’s in the world, one of which (a 9.6) had sold for $126,500 back in 2002. The Overstreet Comic Book Price Guide — the bible on such matters — estimated an 8.5 copy to be worth somewhere between $36,500 and $70,750.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="comic caper" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wLBhZNvy2syCjRV-IcFGnL91MPQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3872408/spot.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But someone bidding at the Heritage auction was willing to pay significantly more. The comic had been low-balled at first, going for $49,293.75 during the auction itself. But after the official bidding closed, private offers flooded in: $65,000, then $75,000. In the end, it sold for $200,000, putting it in the same class as a record-breaking debut &lt;i&gt;Spider-Man &lt;/i&gt;that had sold a few years earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;All Star&lt;/i&gt; #3 wasn’t the only mid-tier comic suddenly going for outrageous prices at the 2012 sale. A &lt;i&gt;Sub-Mariner&lt;/i&gt; #14 (in which the aquatic hero Namor twists apart a Panzer tank at Normandy) sold for $4,182, more than three times its estimated worth. In the very next lot, someone shelled out $5,676.25 for an off-white 6.5 &lt;i&gt;Sub-Mariner &lt;/i&gt;#17 (in which Namor struggles with the Japanese fleet) even though Overstreet pegs an 8.0 copy of the same book at just $1,158.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Absolutely insane!" podboy66 wrote the day after the sale in the Collector’s Society forums, a common online hangout for comics buyers. "I paid $450 for my Subby 17 in 6.0." "What’s up with some of these buyers anyway?" Agent 007 asked. "Makes you wonder if it’s simply a case of bidding fever."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever was after the &lt;i&gt;Sub-Mariners &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;All Star Comics&lt;/i&gt; at the Heritage Auction wasn’t a collector. Their bids were too erratic, they didn’t know the market, and chances were, they weren’t terribly smart. It was also clear that they had a lot of money on their hands — too much money, maybe — and they were eager to spend it. Through months of interviews and hundreds of pages of public documents, &lt;i&gt;The Verge &lt;/i&gt;reconstructed what they were seeing: a multi-million-dollar embezzlement scheme that would ensnare a crooked lawyer, a multinational corporation, and some of the most sought-out comics in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="pencil break" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5wwaT-SAm581ix_ZSTp65-nzs7c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3836132/hr_004.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;"WHACK JOB"&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In 2004, Anthony Chiofalo&lt;/strong&gt; had nearly 20 years of corporate law behind him and a political career in his future. Married with two sons, Chiofalo was squat, clean-cut, and brusque. He’d spent his formative years in the Bronx, and when an assembly district seat opened up in the area, he decided to make a run. "He was pretty determined," says Joe Thompson, a Bronx community activist who also ran in the election. But running as a Republican in the heavily Democratic Bronx was hopeless, and Chiofalo lost badly, pulling a little more than 30 percent of the vote. Thompson can’t remember seeing Chiofalo around the community much after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Chiofalo had "trends of grandiosity and episodic impulsivity and poor judgment."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The failed campaign marked a turning point in Chiofalo’s life — a defeat that precipitated a gradual unraveling. According to state records, his wife served him with divorce papers in August of 2005, followed by an order of protection. Chiofalo broke the order within a few months, and by the next year he was writing notes that would later be described as "hostile, obscene, and derogatory," sending them to his wife, to the children’s guardian — even to a clerk for the judge presiding over the divorce case. Chiofalo eventually sued his wife and about 30 others involved in the divorce proceedings, alleging that they had infringed on his civil rights. The argument was thrown out in court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2008, the state court’s disciplinary committee decided to take action against Chiofalo, on the basis that his letters and frivolous lawsuits proved him unfit to be a lawyer. A letter from a psychiatrist quoted during Chiofalo’s disbarment proceeding said he experienced "trends of grandiosity and episodic impulsivity and poor judgment"; that he would "regress at times of stress and duress, particularly around financial, legal, and family issues." When he did, "his narcissistic defenses come to fore, often to his detriment." One of the dozens of individuals involved in Chiofalo’s civil rights lawsuit put it even more simply: "He’s a whack job. Bad news."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there was one bright spot in his life during that time, it was Susan, a university health professor living in Texas. (Susan requested her maiden name not be used in this piece.) The two had been high school sweethearts and reconnected during Chiofalo’s divorce. In 2007, Susan invited Chiofalo to join her in Texas. Eventually, they moved into a cozy rental at 5802 Oakmoss Trail, in Spring, Texas — a small, green piece of the Houston metropolitan area, with wide open spaces and a population of about 50,000. By 2010, the two were married. Chiofalo seemed to have left his problems behind — he found a new job as in-house counsel for a Japanese construction company called Tadano, a gig that came with a $110,000 salary and new responsibility. Disciplinary Committee records show he lobbied to keep his New York law license, saying that he was seeking psychiatric help, but in October 2010, he was suspended from practicing law in the state for two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Tadano seemed to be involved in more and more litigation&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that Chiofalo’s job at Tadano hit a snag. Tadano was the world leader in rough-terrain cranes, selling huge tank-treaded trucks capable of lifting 160 tons to construction companies from London to Dubai. That globe-spanning business came with a river of legal work, and Chiofalo’s job was to coordinate local firms hired by Tadano, drawing up contracts, reviewing service agreements, and approving payments. But in the months after Chiofalo came on board, Tadano seemed to be involved in more and more litigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March of 2012, the company ordered an investigation into the spike in legal costs. "Our approach initially was trying to ask exactly what went on, and then immediately trace the money flow," says Philip Hilder, a lawyer for Tadano. An employee eventually came across an expenditure that looked off. The bill was from Seidner &amp; Virdone, LLP — a business supposedly located at 5802 Oakmoss Trail. According to a Tadano lawsuit later filed against Chiofalo’s wife, the company only existed in New York — it was the firm Chiofalo retained to work on his divorce proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another company Chiofalo submitted invoices from wasn’t real at all. Tadano alleged it was requesting payments be sent to the address on Oakmoss Trail — the firm’s manager and registered agent was Anthony Chiofalo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chiofalo had created a byzantine structure of revolving transfers to conceal his tracks, laundering money through bank accounts, third-party payments, and the purchase of collectibles. Tadano alleged that in one particularly daring trick, he sent a retainer letter to the company requesting $15,000 for an attorney. The "attorney" was Chiofalo’s landlord. Tadano had cut a check that paid six months of rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;The "attorney" was Chiofalo’s landlord. Tadano had cut a check that paid six months of rent&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tadano assessed the damage, adding up all the suspicious checks that had flown from the company’s accounts to each of Chiofalo’s fronts. Nearly $9 million had vanished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two months after the start of the investigation, a higher-up at Tadano approached Chiofalo, asking him to explain himself. Chiofalo produced records — spreadsheets, with billable hours — but the law firms listed would turn out to be fakes. Chiofalo told people he had enlisted the services of Michael Maio — whom he touted as a "super lawyer," licensed with seven State Bars. But Maio never existed; he was no more than a resume, cobbled together from an East Coast lawyer’s accomplishments and a photograph of a West Coast lawyer. Maio was Chiofalo’s mother’s maiden name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the company never had a chance to ask about all of the inconsistencies. The day after he was confronted, Chiofalo didn’t show up to work and stopped answering his phone. As soon as he knew he’d been caught, the lawyer disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="comic caper" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aiF2bF6XAV7MofwOJIGpwpFEcw8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3896394/02.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;THE MUSEUM&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do you stash&lt;/strong&gt; $9 million if you don’t want anyone to find it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tadano hired a private investigator named Bryan Vaclavik to follow the money. A 15-year veteran of the Harris County District Attorney’s office, Vaclavik specialized in fraud cases. He discovered wire transfers from Chiofalo to a "Heritage Auctions," and when investigators at Tadano checked the records for Chiofalo’s work phone, they found that he had been making regular contact with a local storage facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;What the police uncovered was astonishing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 8th, the police arrived with a warrant to search seven climate-controlled units in Spring, Texas’ Four Seasons Self Storage facility. The compound sits on a flat, sunny stretch of concrete just a few miles west of Interstate 45. What they uncovered there was astonishing: The first unit was packed with sports memorabilia, signed helmets, and baseball cards. The second unit had a makeshift study space, full of furniture and books. The third unit had six framed Texas flags and a shadowbox arrangement of photographs of Mussolini, among the flood of other memorabilia. The fourth had more figurines, sports photographs, and paintings depicting scenes from the Bible and World War Two. The fifth unit was mostly baseball cards, along with photographs of Robert De Niro, Phil Jackson, and Mussolini. The sixth unit had statuettes of Batman, Iron Man, Conan the Barbarian, and, again, Mussolini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt; &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Comics Young Allies" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HK4WH71fa_zC0V0XYdavotSQUAE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3896376/Young_Allies.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Young Allies #1, published in 1941&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, in the seventh unit, there were the comics: nearly 50 boxes of them, drawn from every era and genre with seemingly no logic to the collection. The Monkees and &lt;i&gt;Star Wars&lt;/i&gt; comic books &amp;nbsp;— worth a few dollars, if that — sat next to nine different early &lt;i&gt;Detective Comics &lt;/i&gt;issues, a 1940 &lt;i&gt;Batman&lt;/i&gt; #2, a &lt;i&gt;Young Allies&lt;/i&gt; #1, and a specialty comic from the 1940 World’s Fair. A later search turned up a copy of &lt;i&gt;Action Comics &lt;/i&gt;#1, where Superman makes his first appearance — one of the most coveted and expensive comic books of all time. Tadano’s money had been transformed, taken from legal bills and embezzled into merchandise. The haul was worth millions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigators weren’t convinced Chiofalo had spent all of that cash on his own. Tadano alleged that Chiofalo’s wife had been in on the scheme. Harris County DA investigator Dustin Deutsch called Susan a few weeks after Chiofalo disappeared. She said she didn’t know where her husband was and hadn’t seen him in a month. Through what Deutsch described as an anonymous tip, he discovered she had a one-way plane ticket to New York leaving the following day. Was she flying back to meet her husband in the Bronx? He rushed to get a warrant and searched the Chiofalo home the same day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The home resembled an extension of the storage unit: it was "overrun with stacks and piles of boxes and packages," addressed to one of Chiofalo’s fictitious companies, a civil complaint from Tadano would allege. "The interior of their rental home was so crowded that it resembled a museum more than a residence." Investigators said they found checks and other financial documents made out to Chiofalo, Susan, and the fictitious lawyer Maio, while "forged invoices" were found "in clear view."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, Tadano would allege, the Chiofalos used the embezzled funds to buy a $48,000 Lexus, a $44,000 Toyota pickup, and a 10,000-square-foot home for $609,000 that they would remodel. One Chiofalo-linked cashier’s check for $21,000 had gone straight to a furniture store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The police moved to arrest Susan, with Chiofalo still on the run. (Susan filed for divorce the following month.) Chiofalo was charged in absentia with felony theft, with bail preemptively set at $18 million. Under the criminal complaint against him, the "ARREST DATE" section said simply, "TO BE."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="pencil break" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5wwaT-SAm581ix_ZSTp65-nzs7c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3836132/hr_004.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="comic caper" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JwURNh0PV38dKiTpPm_DVJ86TA4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3872382/spot2.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;PLASTIC COFFINS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like a famous painting,&lt;/strong&gt; a rare comic is hard to fence. Only a handful of buyers in the US handle big-ticket sales, and most shops keep scans of every comic for simple safety reasons. Even the most pristine comics are unique, marked with subtle wrinkles, stains, and clouds of mold known as "foxing." Those marks make it easy to follow a single comic as it moves from sale to sale. "It’s almost like fingerprints," says Buddy Saunders, who operates Lone Star Comics in Dallas. "If it shows up on eBay and it was stolen from us, we know." Big auction sites do the same, in part because of return fraud, in which a scammer will purchase a valuable comic and try to return a forgery. If the wrinkles don’t match the scan, the buyer is in serious trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, a business called the Certified Guaranty Company (or CGC) has made fraud even harder. If you bought a comic book from an auction house within the last decade, it probably came in one of CGC’s distinctive plastic shells, complete with a two-digit condition rating, a serial number, and a hologram for authentication. The shells make it impossible to read the comic (critics call them "plastic coffins"), but they offer strong protections against damage and theft. Barcodes make for easy tracking, and "de-slabbing" a comic will make almost any buyer suspicious. If that buyer wants to look the comic up, it’s easy to find recent sales in an auction site’s database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;Deutsch’s specialty was evidence: he taught forensics classes at a nearby community college&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If officials were going to use comics to catch and prosecute Chiofalo, investigators needed to know which comics he had taken with him, and which he had left behind — a task that fell to DA investigator Dustin Deutsch. Deutsch’s specialty was evidence: he taught forensics classes at a nearby community college, and his cases made him a regular on the local TV news. His team spent a full week at the sprawling storage complex, cataloging more than 3,600 separate items. Some of the haul entered into evidence as whole boxes, as if the investigators had simply given up on counting it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locked away in one of the storage units Deutsch was searching was an &lt;i&gt;All Star &lt;/i&gt;#3  — the one that had cost Chiofalo $200,000. Somehow, that comic never made it onto the evidence list. No one noticed the omission. By the time the investigators closed the doors on the storage units at the end of the week, the comic wasn’t there. It was missing, along with an &lt;i&gt;All Winners &lt;/i&gt;#1 and a box of other titles that had mysteriously dropped off the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="comic caper" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5hpZ-DpYtlxNsiMSkmNbX6Ebjxs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3872388/03.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;ALL WINNERS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On August 11th, 2012 &lt;/strong&gt;— three months after Chiofalo vanished — a man named Lonnie Blevins walked into Wizard World’s Chicago Comic Convention looking to unload a box of comics. He worked with Deutsch as a DA investigator in Harris County, sporting the same tight-cropped haircut and square build as his colleague. He was part of the team sorting through Chiofalo’s storage units, although it would be another two weeks before they turned in their official report. But today, he was at the con on personal business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, Chicago Comic-Con takes over the the Donald E. Stephens Convention Center, a stadium-sized concrete box sandwiched between airport hotels on the northwest outskirts of Chicago. This was the third day. William Shatner and Stan Lee made appearances, along with the world’s largest playable Pac Man machine. But for comics, the real action was in the booths, where buyers came from across the country to check out any interesting books that might be for sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blevins brought with him a full box of loose comics, none of them in CGC slabs. Some of his comics were real gems, like an &lt;i&gt;All Star &lt;/i&gt;#3 and an &lt;i&gt;All Winners&lt;/i&gt; #1, but the box was all over the map in terms of condition and quality. Without slabs, buyers were suspicious, but he reassured them. He was a cop back in Texas — he showed them his badge, and let them scan it in case they needed to find him later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt; &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Comics All Winners" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h_PWh30-9YZvU3xUYmrq2Za7z_c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3896402/All_Winners.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class="caption"&gt;All Winners #1, published in 1941&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, how often do you see an &lt;i&gt;All Star&lt;/i&gt; #3, let alone an unslabbed one? The Flash! The Green Lantern! Johnny Thunder! Dr. Fate! It was a rare book and an expensive one, too: after all, just a few months earlier, an&lt;i&gt; All Star &lt;/i&gt;#3 had sold for $200,000 in a private Heritage sale. There was some light foxing — a cloud of mold toward the bottom of the front cover — but otherwise it was in good condition: an 8.0 or even an 8.5 by the look of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, maybe buying such a big title without a CGC box was asking for trouble. "It was very strange," one of the buyers remembered later. "Nobody would crack that book out and sell it raw." But the book was going cheap. Maybe Blevins just didn’t know what he had. Sometimes you just get lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blevins left the con with $30,000 in cash and another $40,000 split between nine checks. The investigator said he was going through a nasty divorce, and was worried his ex-wife might raise trouble over any checks for more than $10,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about that foxing? When the buyers took their comics home, they noticed something strange: the &lt;i&gt;All Star&lt;/i&gt; #3 that had sold in February had the same imperfections. In fact, it was the same book. But that book was slabbed — it had a barcode and provenance, sold to a private buyer who wouldn’t have deslabbed it without a reason. Had they bought stolen property?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was worse. They had bought stolen evidence. The book had come direct from Chiofalo’s storage unit, smuggled out under the nose of the Harris County DA — and according to prosecutors, Blevins and Deutsch worked together to smuggle them out. More than $150,000 in comics had disappeared from the storage unit, and Blevins had spent the summer selling them at comics conventions across the country. The books were deslabbed to throw investigators off the trail, but even without the barcode, the cover gave it away. Collectors search for flawless comics, but it’s the imperfections that give them an identity, and this imperfection placed Blevins at the scene of a crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="comic caper" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fywks5uwbiWISIdJPqNHnObgquU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3872386/04.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A SUITCASE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meanwhile, Chiofalo spent the&lt;/strong&gt; summer on the run. Months went by, and leads dried up. He had taken hundreds of thousands of dollars with him — with that much money, maybe he never needed to come back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, one day in December 2012, just after 2PM, a man in a black sweatshirt walked into the police headquarters of Newport, Rhode Island, carrying a large black suitcase. He told an officer at the counter that there was a warrant out for his arrest. Police ran a search: "Chiofalo" — wanted for aggravated larceny in the state of Texas. He had been on the run for seven months. He told officers that he was carrying cash, although "he wasn’t sure about the amount of money he had," Lt. William Fitzgerald told &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; $100,000? $125,000?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;In Chiofalo's bag, they found $55,000. In the suitcase, $95,000&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was arrested, booked, sent to Cell No. 1, and had his possessions processed: a Rolex watch, two cellphones, a laptop, a bag, and the suitcase. In the bag, they found $55,000. In the suitcase, $95,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chiofalo was eventually extradited back to Texas, but in the seven months since he’d fled, the case against him had gone to shambles. Evidence had gone missing, one of the investigators was under federal indictment, and a special prosecutor had to be brought in to press the case impartially. When Chiofalo appeared in court, he looked haggard, barely recognizable as the fresh-faced lawyer who had run for office 10 years earlier. Under his orange jumpsuit, intricate sleeve tattoos ran down both his forearms. His lawyer blamed the DA’s evidence thefts for trial delays, and pushed for reduced bail. It was hard to disagree. After the hearing, Chiofalo’s bail was reduced from $18 million to just $150,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eager to avoid trial, the prosecution arranged a plea deal, and in May 2014, a Harris County Court judge sentenced Chiofalo to 40 years in prison, up for parole in about eight. According to reports, he would’ve had a better deal, but decided against giving up millions that are still unaccounted for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caught red-handed, Lonnie Blevins plead guilty to federal charges of evidence tampering. Deutsch quit the DA’s office as soon as the charges came down, and is currently standing trial for felony theft and tampering with evidence. The DA put 125 cases the officers had worked on under re-examination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Comic All Star No 3" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DQdG7yE3rGopo7bK7QSQPqQHYhE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3896408/All_Star_No_3.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The All Star #3 copy originally purchased by Chiofalo at auction for $200,000 in its CGC slab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are the comics. The three Chicago buyers, having purchased stolen goods, are now out $70,000. ("It was a bad and expensive experience," one buyer told &lt;i&gt;The Verge&lt;/i&gt;. "That is all I will say.") Tadano retrieved most of the material from the storage facilities and sold them back through the same auction houses where Chiofalo had first bought them. The only exception were comics like &lt;i&gt;All Star&lt;/i&gt; #3, which had been sold by Blevins and were kept for evidence in Deutsch’s trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Susan had the charges against her dropped for lack of evidence and her criminal records expunged. The civil lawsuit, Susan wrote in an email, "was merely a legal formality, designed so I could sign over to Tadano all the property acquired post-marriage; and for intimidation purposes. As I recall, there is quite a bit of embellishment in the narrative."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In correspondence, Susan was eager to close that chapter of her life. "He left a trail of destruction in his path and caused a great deal of pain and suffering to all his loved ones," Susan said. The experience left her with what she called "lifelong PTSD-related scars."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can’t be said if Chiofalo, Deutsch, or Blevins ever read &lt;i&gt;All Star&lt;/i&gt; #3, but if they did, they might have read a tale about a daring heist, foiled by the chapter’s hero, The Atom. In his earliest appearances, The Atom wears a wrestling corset and yellow leotard, armed with no superpowers except a strong sense of morality. In the story, soldiers are transporting a stockpile of government gold to a vault when they’re intercepted by a group of gangsters packing Tommy guns. The gangsters overpower the soldiers, disguising themselves in the stolen uniforms, and drive into the government compound. The guards greet them, and in one small, single panel, guards and crooks are framed together. Dressed the same, their faces void of definition, it’s impossible to tell them apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A note on sourcing: This piece was researched over six months, with public records confirmed by subject interviews wherever possible. The bulk of the information was drawn from court records, particularly the criminal cases against Blevins and Deutsch, as well as the criminal and civil cases against Chiofalo on the civil case against his wife. We also drew from the New York State Departmental Disciplinary Committee’s action against Chiofalo, which resulted in his temporary disbarment in that state. Where warranted, we have removed the names of parties involved so as not to inflict further harm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="credit"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design by &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dylanlathrop"&gt;Dylan Lathrop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited by &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/mvzelenks"&gt;Michael Zelenko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="pencil break" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5wwaT-SAm581ix_ZSTp65-nzs7c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3836132/hr_004.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script src="//use.typekit.net/mhg3psl.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;!--
try{Typekit.load();}catch(e){}
// --&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/22/8870089/texas-comic-book-heist-anthony-chiofalo-tadano"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/22/8870089/texas-comic-book-heist-anthony-chiofalo-tadano</id>
    <author>
      <name>Colin Lecher</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-07-17T10:01:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-17T10:01:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>The search for the perfect music streaming service</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XN8gtaQ3U_-tg3zGyA0pYYrEYcc=/150x0:1770x1080/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46764602/cloud_music_1.0.0.png" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;The biggest ongoing problem in my technological life is when, where, and how to easily listen to music. There are two reasons why this is a problem: 1) music is a vital part of my life — I need a steady stream of new tracks and artists to listen to, and I need to be able to cue up my old favorite songs at crucial moments — and 2) I strongly suspect there is no perfect way to listen to music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Streaming Music Cover" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VGcL4FhHDwCvnphPaUTvuRXvakY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3882912/cloud_music_1.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Stream of the Crop&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A month-long journey to find the best music-streaming service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By Emily Yoshida&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The biggest ongoing&lt;/strong&gt; problem in my technological life is when, where, and how to easily listen to music. There are two reasons why this is a problem: 1) music is a vital part of my life — I need a steady stream of new tracks and artists to listen to, and I need to be able to cue up my old favorite songs at crucial moments — and 2) I strongly suspect there is no perfect way to listen to music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;In the mid-aughts, I developed the most fruitful and healthy relationship I’ve ever had with music&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But sometime in the mid-aughts, I came close. The system I developed then represents the most fruitful and&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;healthy &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;relationship I’ve ever had with music. I spent money on used and new music — a good Amoeba haul would sometimes set me back $40 or $50 — but as a college student in a post-Napster world, I did my fair share of pirating, too, and ripped countless CDs borrowed from the college radio station I worked at. I uploaded my entire music library to my fourth-generation iPod, while still continuing to use the CDs in my stereo at home and in my friends’ cars. Part of my collection was based off recommendations, part of it was made up of canonical must-listens, and some of it was completely random. Some songs I only listened to once; others became my favorite songs of all time. It was during an afternoon of idle browsing at the station that I found the album &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em style="font-size: 1rem; line-height: 1.4;"&gt;Wonder Wonder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; by alt-country singer-songwriter Edith Frost. Most of that album wasn’t really my style, but the fifth track, "Cars and Parties," became a sturdy old friend to me in my first transitory years living in Los Angeles.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, of course, all that hard work and illegal activity has been rendered obsolete. Even if I had a computer with a disc drive, ripping CDs feels as archaic as taping songs from the radio, and downloading illegal MP3s is a headache, even with a lightning-fast cable connection that 2004-me would have died over. Streaming has become the new standard ever since Spotify became available in the US in 2011; other contenders such as Rdio, Rhapsody, and Tidal have tried to win a part of the "every song whenever you want it" market with varying success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caved and signed up for a Spotify Premium account back in 2011; but there are lots of things about the service I find frustrating, disorienting, and impersonal. &lt;i&gt;Is there something better for me out there?&lt;/i&gt; I wondered. In the name of improving the very fabric of my life, I went on a quest to survey the streaming ecosystem, looking for the ultimate service. Over the course of a month, I tried as many other options as I could, spending at least four days with each one. Because the features they all offer were so similar on paper, I knew picking the best service would come down to a matter of interface and ambiance; an intangible addictive aspect more than a list of specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ll be back, I told Spotify. Maybe not. What followed was the streaming music equivalent of a month-long Tinder bender — every bit as mentally and emotionally disorienting. Don’t worry, though. This breakup has a happy ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet wide"&gt;&lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spotify&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Spotify Stitched" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W5C9TGZFMJnuVYp0wUI481mgbGo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3882922/Spotify_Stitched.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the height&lt;/strong&gt; of my struggle with Spotify’s awkward interface, I went through and vengefully counted the taps it took to get into the app, find a song, and play it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tap on Spotify Icon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tap on the Menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tap on Settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tap on Social&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Turn on Private Session&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tap Back to Settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tap Menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tap Search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Enter search query&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tap on Song&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six out of those 10 steps are necessary for turning off Spotify’s social function, a baked-in aspect of the service and a relic of a time when it still seemed like everything should be a social network. Some cling to that aspect of the service, but for me, listening to music is like eating; it’s fun to do with friends, but when you’re doing it by yourself the last thing you want is to be watched. I listen to a lot of dumb utilitarian music when I'm working out, and I’m not ashamed of that; I’m more than happy to discuss the specific merits of Britney Spears’ "Til The World Ends" in casual conversation — I just don’t find much use in telling my friends I listened to the first 3 minutes of deadmau5’s "fn pig" five times in a row as some kind of meditative post-workout intention-setting exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I listen to a lot of dumb utilitarian music when I'm working out, and I’m not ashamed of that&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also, for what it’s worth, prefer not to have my streaming service infer certain things about my taste based on these isolated quirks. Thankfully, recommendations are not really a part of Spotify’s game. There are plenty of curated playlists based on mood, genre, and charts, which are both easily accessible and easily ignorable. For over a year I’ve been subscribed to a Detroit Techno playlist 382 tracks long that I can find conveniently listed with the rest of my personal playlists, but Spotify doesn’t try to shove Plastikman radio stations down my throat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I don’t trust Spotify. In 2012, about a year after I started subscribing, a rift opened up in my account history. I had signed onto the app using a new work computer, only to find that all my saved music and playlists had been lost. Gone. I gradually rebuilt my stockpile, but from that moment on, the ephemerality of everything contained under that tab labeled "My Music" was never lost on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify is purely fine. But I think my entire relationship with it can be summed up by that great wipe of 2012 and the fact that for about two years it was automatically shuffling all of my playback, with no apparent option to turn it off. After an afternoon of failed troubleshooting, I gave up, and for the next year I had to manually tap on the next sequential track whenever I wanted to listen to an album in order. It was a pain, but a pain I accepted, because from that point on I associated Spotify with inconvenience and disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use if you:&lt;/strong&gt; Would like to easily ignore curated playlists / stations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t use if you:&lt;/strong&gt; Hate the idea of making your listening habits social&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet wide"&gt;&lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TIDAL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Tidal Stitched" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P1DMcUqnrLUMPNhJSqb7Y5E4-XU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3884384/Tidal_Stitched__1_.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I appreciate Tidal’s&lt;/strong&gt; honesty. In New York, much of my listening takes place underground, away from an LTE signal, so offline listening is crucial. On Spotify, offline listening feels a little like alchemy — you can turn it on, and if the stars align correctly and your heart chakra is balanced, you may in fact be able to listen to a song you like on your next subway commute. When I turned on offline listening on Tidal, however, a message instantly popped up telling me I didn’t have enough space on my phone to use the feature. This was annoying, but at least it was a clear response. However, no matter how many files I deleted off my phone, I could never make enough room. I hopped back over to Spotify for a second, and sure enough, I succeeded in getting four songs onto my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;once I go underground, the test begins. Is it still playing music after a minute?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t sign up for Tidal Hi-Fi, but still, those files must be huge. Another important test of any streaming service is how long it plays music once you’ve gone out of range: every morning I cue up music for the 5-minute walk to my train station, and once I go underground, the test begins. Is it still playing music after a minute? After 5 minutes? Unlike Spotify, which usually banks the next couple songs on deck, giving me up to 10 minutes worth of music underground, Tidal appears to be streaming everything a la carte. Even above ground, this leads to noticeable pauses between songs, pauses long enough that sometimes I have to check and make sure I still have a connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This contributes to a broader, less quantifiable sense that Tidal doesn’t really have my back. Sure, its catalog is more or less identical to Spotify’s (though I did find some gaps — Jamie xx’s &lt;em&gt;In Colour&lt;/em&gt; is tragically missing, so I listened to Kacey Musgraves’ &lt;em&gt;Pageant Material&lt;/em&gt; instead), but it seems to be investing more of its effort in the star power of its guest playlists and exclusive content — which remains seriously wanting. (Why did Rihanna, a Tidal artist, release her "Bitch Better Have My Money" video to Vevo instead of Tidal?) If Spotify is the sturdy, unglamorous Hampton Inn, Tidal is a slapped-together luxury hotel with a touchscreen thermostat but no towels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Use if you: &lt;/b&gt;Need to know what J. Cole is listening to this week&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Don’t use if you: &lt;/b&gt;Are a snob about anything besides lossless audio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet wide"&gt;&lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rdio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Rdio Stitched" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MX68JYORjnF1Conli7t4eqKGvfY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3882968/Rdio_Stitched.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opening Rdio for&lt;/strong&gt; the first time on my phone felt like stepping into a tastefully minimalist coffee shop. I wanted to touch everything. After spending a few days in Tidal’s dark, messy, Helvetica-dominated world, Rdio felt like suddenly being among grown-ups. This is probably not accidental; Rdio is one of the oldest players in this game, having launched their app in 2010. It’s a hybrid of encyclopedic streaming libraries like Spotify and more randomized streaming services like Pandora. Rdio wants you to take your hand off the wheel and let it curate a handful of personalized stations to your liking — while still giving you the ability to build your own "library" of albums and songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t too different from Tidal’s philosophy, but Rdio is more oriented to the user than to the tastemakers and celebrities it's cobbled together in its playlist section. For that reason, I was way more open to submitting to its whims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I do like to dabble in semi-randomized music experiences now and then — the less taps to get music in my ears the better, right? As an experiment, I selected Lana Del Rey as a favorite artist, and fired up Lana Del Rey Radio, a concept that should seem familiar to any Pandora user. The first song that came up was LDR’s "Ride" — so far, so Lana — but after that, I was horrified to see Ed Sheeran’s maudlin "The A Team" pop up. I see the algorithmic reasons for this: singer-songwriters who talk about troubled heroines! But I want to hear Lana sing about herself as a troubled heroine, not Sheeran’s obliviously earnest ode to a homeless addict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;q&gt;So far, so Lana &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rdio also lets you "download" albums for use offline, a feature which I used to put Miguel’s new album &lt;em&gt;Wildheart&lt;/em&gt; on my phone. Adding anything beyond that proved a challenge with my consistently at-capacity storage space, so this wasn’t a feature I got a whole lot of mileage out of. Still, with all of these offline listening options, it’s hard to avoid the feeling that we’ve taken a convoluted path back to something we perfected years ago: putting goddamn mp3s on goddamn portable devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Rdio is just Tidal with a more finessed UI and preprogrammed stations that happened to overlap more with my interests (I got a lot of mileage out of DJ-Kicks Radio). Both services are taking something Spotify pioneered — putting a huge library of songs at your disposal — and trying to add value via the quality of curation. It’s almost as if Tidal and Rdio have figured that Spotify perfected the library, and thus they haven’t bothered putting any resources into meaningfully improving the experience of using it. Would a hotly anticipated new player in the market be able to crack the code?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use if you:&lt;/strong&gt; Will mostly be using your service for personalized and curated radio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t use if you:&lt;/strong&gt; Will never use your service for personalized radio and curation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet wide"&gt;&lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apple Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Apple Stitched" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kFeUhldPqEpTbmyNqcqLQOKgffM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3882972/Apple_Stitched.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At 11AM on&lt;/strong&gt; June 30th, 2015, I began my iOS update. When my iPhone reset I would have access to Apple’s long-awaited streaming-music service, and I was standing on a cliff, arms outstretched, waiting for my corporate overlords to beam me up into their mothership and carry me off to a land of unlimited music and radio curated by people with better taste than me. As a relatively frequent iTunes user, I figured that adding streaming to the equation would automatically make Apple my one-stop shop for music consumption. I didn’t &lt;a target="new" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/9/8748699/apple-music-beats-radio-spotify-streaming-files-ownership"&gt;&lt;em&gt;like &lt;/em&gt;that&lt;/a&gt;, but I assumed I was powerless against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I was standing on a cliff, arms outstretched, waiting for my corporate overlords to beam me up&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I was struck by upon opening Apple Music was how much stuff there was. Hot Tracks! Editors' Playlists! Songs to Make Up To! After mere minutes browsing through its various byways, Apple Music had cemented itself as the Cheesecake Factory menu of streaming options, surprising for a company that’s built a cult around its minimalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, a lot of these corners of Apple Music are actually pretty intelligently curated. But there are so many of them that it’s easy to lose track of them. I had found some random zoned-out workout playlist at one point, and when I went to go find it again (having foolishly forgotten to fave it) I couldn’t remember if it was New, or For Me, or on the Curators' list. And merging your iTunes library with your streaming library is much more confusing than it should be; the playlists I saved from Apple’s extensive playlist library often vanished into thin air. (Due to what appeared to be a bug, I also completely lost the ability to create new playlists of my own.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there’s one fun, if not flawlessly successful aspect of Apple Music, it’s Beats 1 Radio, which brings some of the in-the-moment tastemaker-driven discovery back to music. I had to admit, it had started to get lonely wandering around these faceless, vast virtual music malls. Beats 1 brought back a fraction of the unpredictable joy of a human curator; after a day or two checking in, I quickly learned that I enjoyed Julie Adenuga’s show more than Zane Lowe’s, and the New York "city blocks" were better than the Los Angeles ones. It’s a small pool to navigate, but it mirrored the kind of analog legwork I had trained myself to do growing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Music overlays iTunes’ existing "star" rating system with a binary "heart" system — stars are how "good" you think the music is, while hearts represent whether or not you want that song to be a part of your personal music delivery algorithm. This inspired some discussion among folks here at &lt;i&gt;The Verge&lt;/i&gt;: What is a one star + heart song? What’s a five star + no heart song? It began to dawn on me that a broader shift was happening across all these streaming platforms: value was being placed on how often a song was being played, but not how much we actually like it. Björk is one of my favorite artists of all time, but I’m not going to tell Apple Music to deliver me a lot of random Björk songs; most times are not optimal Björk-listening times. Meanwhile, I’m playing a Justin Bieber and Diplo song three times a day. I bought &lt;i&gt;Post&lt;/i&gt; as a physical album in high school; I’m never going to pay for a download of the Jack Ü album. And I suspect many other people have experienced a version of this. What do streaming platforms think they’re learning about our listening habits? Am I contributing to a future pseudo-meritocratic music dystopia? Should I get out while I still can?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use if you:&lt;/strong&gt; Like the idea of contributing to a future pseudo-meritocratic music dystopia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t use if you:&lt;/strong&gt; Use sharing functions frequently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet wide"&gt;&lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Google Stitched" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6NsMT5NPUIo1GjvoQUkfhJ-k4yI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3883040/Google_Stitched.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once upon a time,&lt;/strong&gt; I used Google Music — I vaguely remember uploading my entire music collection to the cloud in 2011. This was during what I recall being the second-best phase of How I Did Music in my life — I bought DRM-free mp3s off of Amazon (and acquired them through other creative means, too, of course) and drag and dropped them onto my Android phone. There was no syncing or streaming or clouds; these were all my files that I uploaded to a device via a USB cable. I rarely actually used Google Music because I was scared of the data charges, and it seemed redundant to select the library of music that I had hand-picked to actually live on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after several years of Apple just straight up losing many of my music purchases, I guess I expected my Google Music archive to be gone when I logged on for the first time in years. Giant data managing systems just naturally lose your data over time, right? Yahoo deletes my old mail account because I haven’t logged into it in years; Spotify just randomly decides to wipe my entire listening history. Somehow over years of life on the internet, I’ve convinced myself that that’s just nature happening. If I leave a Little Caesars pizza outside for four years, I can’t expect to come back and still have it be hot n’ ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;q&gt;If I leave a Little Caesars pizza outside for four years I can’t expect to come back and still have it be hot n’ ready&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I opened Google Play Music and was presented with a list of "recently played" songs ported flawlessly from 2011, I was filled with a warm, pleasant sense of continuity that is frequently missing in this crazy, mixed-up, on-demand world. Even if it was still streaming them from some remote server, it was reassuring to see a collection of music and cover art that I knew I had personally amassed and organized. Much of it was music I hadn’t listened to or even thought about for years, but I was more than happy to be reminded of it. I cued up Battles’ 2007 debut &lt;em&gt;Mirrored&lt;/em&gt; and left for work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Play’s interface feels familiar and intuitive, mostly because it feels like so many other Google apps on my phone. If Apple Music was a Cheesecake Factory menu, Google Music is the board at In N Out: your choices are slim and to the point: "Listen Now" (a selection of curated playlists for when you don’t want to think), Top Charts and New Releases (self-explanatory), and My Library. (If I had one gripe, it’s that artists and albums and playlists are listed as thumbnail blocks instead of lists, but it’s all still alphabetized and relatively easy to sort through.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If Apple Music was a Cheesecake Factory menu, Google Music is the board at In N Out&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’ve got to subsist on a streaming service, I’d much rather be streaming my own library of music and supplementing that with Google’s own encyclopedia. I’ve created my own filter on the years and decades of music available to stream, and when I want something I don’t have, I just toggle over to search and fill in the gaps. The music I chose to make readily available for myself throughout the reign of the mp3 is a kind of personal history; seeing an old Microphones EP I ripped in 2004 alongside a sleek, anonymous jogging track I starred earlier this year makes me feel like I’m experiencing music in my own subjective, illogical context again — not merely clicking play on every hot new release the service throws at me, or whatever "favorite artist" of mine I happen to remember with my Twitter-addled, increasingly faulty 2015 brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, I’ll be walking somewhere at night and remember my old lonesome buddy, "Cars and Parties." For whatever reason, the track was never on Spotify — I’d check occasionally over the years just to make sure. As I walked home after my first day on Google Music, I flipped open to my Library, found Edith Frost under my artists, and, for the first time in years, heard the snare drum chugging in my ears. I was still beaming music into my brain from some faraway server that was probably watching all my activity with more judgy eyebrow-raising than any snobby record store clerk, but at least it was my music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use if you: &lt;/strong&gt;Have a large mp3 library you’d like to keep in your life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t use if you:&lt;/strong&gt; Have the sinking suspicion that all of this ends in uploading your entire life to a corporate-owned cloud, and you’re seriously considering getting into vinyl and moving to the woods, in which case, I’m glad I could help&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="credit"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;* *&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mvzelenks" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Zelenko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script src="//use.typekit.net/jeb6huv.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;!--
try{Typekit.load();}catch(e){}
// --&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/17/8981783/best-music-streaming-service-2015-spotify-apple-google-tidal-rdio"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/17/8981783/best-music-streaming-service-2015-spotify-apple-google-tidal-rdio</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emily Yoshida</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-07-09T10:02:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-09T10:02:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Why are the most important people in media reading The Awl?</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d7ODKNN2QopLj02AiO8kdtspfVY=/400x0:5120x3147/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46699108/Cover_Edit.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;In March, at the Code/Media conference in Dana Point, California, some of the most powerful people in media found themselves discussing an unsettling story published two weeks prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Awl Cover Edit" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FgeNKjMfGpU_TtGrk96dtsoMiO0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3856222/Cover_Edit.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Website, Profiled&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why are the most important people in media reading The Awl?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By Josh Dzieza&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In February,&lt;/strong&gt; at the Code/Media&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; conference in Dana Point, California, some of the most powerful people in media found themselves discussing an unsettling story published two weeks prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2015/02/the-next-internet-is-tv"&gt;The piece&lt;/a&gt; predicted that the future of the internet looked a lot like the television industry: websites would atrophy, and publications would become disembodied producers of content for large social networks like Facebook. "If in five years I’m just watching NFL-endorsed ESPN clips through a syndication deal with a messaging app, and Vice is just an age-skewed Viacom with better audience data, and I’m looking up the same trivia on Genius instead of Wikipedia, and ‘publications’ are just content agencies that solve temporary optimization issues for much larger platforms," the author wrote, "what will have been point of the last 20 years of creating things for the web?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recode&lt;/em&gt;’s Peter Kafka used the piece to prod Chris Cox, Facebook’s chief product officer. Cox denied that Facebook was trying to devour the internet. But &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt; founder Nick Denton brought the piece up later in the conference, endorsing its central idea. "Every publisher has to make a choice as to whether they’re going to be a content provider within somebody else’s ecosystem, on somebody else’s platform and subject to somebody else’s algorithm, somebody else’s rules," Denton said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; stands counter to the prevailing trends in the media industry&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The piece hit a nerve in an industry trying to figure out where it sits in an internet centralizing around gigantic platforms. It was written by John Herrman, a journalist who established his name as a tech blogger, but it wasn’t published in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Columbia Journalism Review&lt;/em&gt;, publications with long histories of media criticism, or by any of the big new media companies at the heart of these changes. It appeared on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Awl&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an offbeat site with a small readership and a wry sensibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2009 by Choire Sicha, Alex Balk, and David Cho,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; stands counter to the prevailing trends in the media industry, commenting skeptically on the conventions of the wider web while running a mix of stories that are both wide-ranging and unabashedly specific: writerly reviews of the &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/slug/weather-reviews"&gt;previous day’s weather&lt;/a&gt;, deconstructions of &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2015/06/screaming-cornpops-who-are-tearing-apart-society"&gt;minion memes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/tag/negroni-season"&gt;tirades against negronis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/tag/the-fucking-moon"&gt;the Moon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2015/05/not-knowing"&gt;personal essays&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/tag/listicle-without-commentary"&gt;deadpan lists&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2013/07/rape-joke-patricia-lockwood"&gt;poetry&lt;/a&gt;. The site’s tone, knowingly smart and aloof from the news cycle, is especially popular among people who work in media, and it has become a farm team for larger publications. Lately, under the editorship of Herrman and Matt Buchanan, it also publishes some of the most incisive criticism about the ongoing collision of media and technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt;’s unique position is partly the result of its business practices and goals. The site has expanded into a network, with the comedy site&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://splitsider.com/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Splitsider&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; the women-oriented site&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://thehairpin.com/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Hairpin&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and the personal finance site&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://thebillfold.com/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Billfold&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. At a time when venture capital feels abundant, it’s entirely self funded and profitable, though with a very thin cushion. In an industry obsessed with rapid growth, the editors are wary of scaling up. When the company expands — as it plans to do soon with a new parenting site run by former &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt; editor Brian Barrett — it does so cautiously, by partnering with writers. A few months ago,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; gained a newsletter by bringing Laura Olin’s &lt;em&gt;Everything Changes&lt;/em&gt; under the site’s banner, and now Buchanan and Herrman are launching a podcast, which they’ll host, record, and edit themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; has found a way to make being small work in an industry that favors scale and mass appeal, and it’s become the sort of place where writers like Herrman and Buchanan can stand back and watch the content dynamo churn. But the company is subject to the same forces they’ve been warning about, and the people who built it are thinking about how to navigate the weird new internet taking shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Matt Couch" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z6hoOURiTJT1KxK1Y7HcUZIy1Kg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3856596/06.22.15_The_Verge__The_Awl_0223.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;John Herrman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In April,&lt;/strong&gt; I met up with Herrman and Buchanan at an empty hotel bar not far from &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; office in Downtown Brooklyn. Buchanan, in a crisp oxford buttoned to the neck, his red hair pushed to the side, ordered a ginger ale. Herrman, also red-haired and looking slightly more rumpled in a worn green sweatshirt and jeans, got a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herrman and Buchanan think the media industry is due for a reckoning. The transition from media hosted on websites to media built around social platforms is more profound than people realize, Herrman says. As more content is published directly onto Facebook, users will gradually lose a sense of who’s producing what. The most consequential journalism becomes just another unit of content in a single stream of music videos, movie trailers, updates from friends and relatives, advertisements, and viral tidbits from sites adept at gaming fast-changing algorithms and behaviors. Readerships that seem large now will turn out to be as ephemeral as Snapchats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I think John tends to be ahead of these things because he reads them as science fiction of the present," Buchanan says. "That’s a lot of what &lt;i&gt;The Awl &lt;/i&gt;does now," Herrman agrees. "Our entire economy is just a giant science fiction writing prompt."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"Our entire economy is just a giant science fiction writing prompt."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two have worked together for so long, first at &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;, then at &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt;, that they’re widely referred to as "the gingers." ("Actually they’re one big ginger man in a trench coat that people mistake for two people," says Adam Frucci, who worked with them at &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt; and now edits &lt;em&gt;Splitsider&lt;/em&gt;.) Herrman is genial and goes on frequent flights of theoretical fancy that often end in apocalypse and laughter. Buchanan is more reserved, punching in with acerbic jokes. When they get on one of their favorite topics — Amazon, Uber, Facebook — they bounce back and forth in an accelerating game of dystopian repartee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon cities will be stratified into classes of on-demand laborers, Herrman says, "app playgrounds" zoned by service radii. It’s going to get more interesting when you replace those people with robots, Buchanan says, adding that everyone will be eating soylent while the rich eat solid foods in surge-priced restaurants. "I can’t wait for the progressively priced food market," Herrman says, with genuine enthusiasm, "that’s going to be great." Struggling to keep a straight face, Buchanan describes college lectures with professors delivering sponsored native ads indistinguishable from the course — environmental science brought to you by Exxon. "In-app purchases for college! College premium! I can’t wait!" Herrman says. "The future is going to be amazing," Buchanan says, dryly. "I’m so glad I’ll be dead."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two got their start at &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;’s tech site, &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;: Buchanan in 2006, while still at NYU, and Herrman in 2008, while at the University of Edinburgh. It was classic gadget blogging in a very different internet, and they excelled at it. They wrote up to a dozen posts a day — "&lt;a href="http://gizmodo.com/5726124/what-is-gorilla-glass"&gt;What is Gorilla Glass?&lt;/a&gt;," "&lt;a href="http://gizmodo.com/5812641/the-greatestest-mouse-ever-reincarnated"&gt;The Greatestest Mouse Ever, Reincarnated&lt;/a&gt;"&amp;nbsp;— which readers found by checking the site’s homepage, through RSS, or by following links from other blogs. "They were the two smartest people, the most talented people that came through that site," says Brian Lam, who ran &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt; at the time. Lam went on to launch &lt;em&gt;The Wirecutter&lt;/em&gt;, a gadget review site for The Awl&amp;nbsp;Network that now runs independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="matt buchanan" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ruecOZpp4M9a8bWO0-ve1lsOcSM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3857154/06.22.15_The_Verge__The_Awl_0396.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;Matt Buchanan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, as social platforms like Facebook and Twitter were becoming major sources of traffic, Buchanan and Herrman left &lt;i&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/i&gt; to start &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/mattbuchanan/fwd-fwd-fwd-hello"&gt;tech section&lt;/a&gt;. There, Buchanan did close-readings of Twitter design changes while Herrman took an interest in Facebook’s effect on the media. Herrman "was one of the first reporters to understand that the genre known as ‘media reporting’ exists now largely within the larger context of companies typically thought of as tech companies," says &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt; editor-in-chief Ben Smith, citing Herrman’s &lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/jwherrman/facebook-social-readers-are-all-collapsing#.vw6axvVqE"&gt;piece on Facebook’s social readers&lt;/a&gt;, a partnership that drove traffic to news sites until Facebook redesigned the feature. Buchanan went to &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; for a year, then rejoined Herrman at &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; in 2014, after they were both approached by the site’s co-founder Choire Sicha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buchanan does most of the editing, while writing about architecture, technology, and drinks. Herrman has stayed on the Facebook beat, now covering&amp;nbsp;the subject as an outsider. "You can’t write about media and the internet at &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt; without torturing yourself over what it means," he says. He writes with the tone of an anthropologist studying the bewildering behaviors of the content industry: the "sacred ritual" of embedding &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2014/11/the-john-oliver-video-sweepstakes-finale"&gt;John Oliver clips&lt;/a&gt; that every site performs on Mondays, the dozens of identical posts that spring up around the same &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2014/06/story-covered"&gt;Twitter gaffe&lt;/a&gt;, the collective rush to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2014/09/take-time"&gt;dash off opinions&lt;/a&gt; about whatever topic everyone else is covering. Herrman’s 10,000-foot view of the industry is disquieting: publications start to look strangely similar, hazily defined organizations jostling for a spot in the feeds of social platforms. Publications like &lt;em&gt;Upworthy&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2014/10/cash-and-anxiety-on-the-weird-new-internet"&gt;spammier clones&lt;/a&gt; grow rapidly using formats tailored for Facebook’s News Feed, only to plummet with every opaque tweak to the platform’s algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"I think things are probably much, much worse industry-wise than people acknowledge."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I think things are probably much, much worse industry-wise than people acknowledge. It is, to the web, what the web was to what came before it," Herrman later says of the shift to platforms. "If in the process of adapting to it you also lost track of what you were intending to do, then you are just an instrument attached to someone else’s machine, this little weirdly adapted thing that will be disposed of once someone gets around to fixing it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone is so grim. Large companies like &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt; and, well, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s parent company Vox Media, are forming partnerships with platforms to let them host content directly, in the belief that the relationship will be mutually beneficial. "I am definitely thinking about similar things," BuzzFeed CEO Jonah Peretti says of Herrman’s writing. "I enjoy reading his columns because I’m also trying to understand the changes happening in the media industry — though I tend to be more optimistic than he is."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Herrman and Buchanan are wary of the distorting effects platforms bring. There’s a sense that social sharing is impossible to game, Herrman says, that makes it authentic. But platforms have their own dynamics. People share content that confirms something they believe or that they want people to believe about them. More arbitrarily, certain forms thrive according to the changing metrics of Facebook’s algorithm: time spent off site, or comments. &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2015/06/platform-patched"&gt;Teasingly captioned videos&lt;/a&gt; or quizzes rule for a time, then die off as behaviors and algorithms adjust. Everything is accelerating and nothing lasts for long. At &lt;em&gt;The Awl,&lt;/em&gt; Buchanan and Herrman have found a perch where they can stand back and watch the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I’m ready for a big storm," Herrman says, putting down his beer and launching into an exaggerated vision of the future. "Everyone wakes up, and it’s just sand. And most people die, but a few survive, and they all walk in different directions. And I’m ready for this to happen every three months. That’s the cool cyberpunk outcome of all this. Everything remakes itself all the time, and then nothing is sustainable, and the idea that you could do any of these things we’re doing now as jobs will be some ridiculous anachronism." &lt;em&gt;The Awl,&lt;/em&gt; he says, laughing, is "the counterexample to entropy that proves the rule. Just wait."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="The Awl Choire" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XPL4CNrE1pNw3-Ei7qrHgH5Ctss=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3856602/06.22.15_The_Verge__The_Awl_0625.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;Choire Sicha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; launched in April&lt;/strong&gt; of 2009 out of Choire Sicha’s East Village apartment. The publishing industry, weakened by the internet, was crumbling as the recession worsened. The magazine &lt;em&gt;Radar&lt;/em&gt; had just closed, putting Sicha and Alex Balk out of work. Rather than write for someone else, they decided to launch their own site, with &lt;em&gt;Radar&lt;/em&gt;’s David Cho as their publisher. Their plan was to hire reporters and cover local news, media, and politics, but they couldn’t get funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"So we were like, fuck it, and just launched like a piece of garbage, like throwing a rock in the ocean," Sicha says, lounging on the couch in &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt;'s office, drinking seltzer. Sicha is a charming speaker, both friendly and mocking, especially when it comes to himself and the company’s haphazard origins. He relishes the ugliness of its early design, a minimal Wordpress blog with a photo of a Butterfinger in lieu of an ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"We were like, fuck it, and just launched like a piece of garbage."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early on, Sicha and Balk would sit at a long dining table, smoking, wearing coats indoors in the winter, and writing post after post. In a stroke of luck, Sicha’s landlord mysteriously vanished and stopped cashing his checks; less luckily, the apartment began to collapse, the ceiling falling into the bathtub. To help finance their venture, Sicha says he stopped paying taxes, running up a six-figure tab with the IRS. "It was terrible," he recalls. "I’ve been broke before. I don’t mind it. It’s something that happens to me sort of regularly in my life, but that was a bad one."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sicha and Balk were among the first professional bloggers, largely by happenstance. (I spoke with Balk on background; he’s never been interviewed for publication. Sicha, on the other hand, spoke freely: "I don’t give a fuck," he said, "I’ll say anything.") Sicha worked as a bartender and in homeless shelters in San Francisco after high school, then as an art dealer in New York. "I liked writing, and I wanted to be a writer, but I was a mess," he says. "I wrote like one paper in high school, and then I didn’t go to college." In his late 20s after moving to New York, he started blogging to stay in touch with a friend back in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;’s Nick Denton hired Sicha to run &lt;em&gt;Fleshbot&lt;/em&gt;, the company’s now-abandoned porn site, then &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt; itself. Meanwhile, Balk was in advertising and writing a culture blog on the side; he landed at &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt; a few years later. Sicha left for&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Observer&lt;/em&gt; after a year, then returned briefly in 2007. The style that he developed at &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;, conversational with bursts of enthusiasm and ironic swerves, exerted a deep influence on the voice of the early web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="The Awl Threesome" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0s48RfCuSxexL9b-gvMxuOrCG9o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3857186/06.22.15_The_Verge__The_Awl_0520.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"That style became internet parlance," says Andrew Womack of &lt;em&gt;The Morning News&lt;/em&gt;, where Sicha freelanced while at &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;. "You almost can’t think of a bigger effect. I can’t look at anyone type an exclamation point without thinking of Choire’s first stint at &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;. It wasn’t snarky; it was honest and had this fuck-it-all attitude I think we’ve all had."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balk and Sicha left &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt; as it began to expand beyond local media gossip. "Nick was starting to figure out that &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt; should grow, and I was like, 'I’m not the right man for this job,'" Sicha says. "I could’ve hired a Neetzan [Zimmerman], but I didn’t know that was what I should be looking for," he says, referring to &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;’s former viral content superstar. "But I think I actually just didn’t want &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt; to grow."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"We just don’t really want any stupid people reading it."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; went up on April 20th with a &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2009/04/social-as-my-saddles-waiting-come-and-jump-on-it"&gt;column by Emily Gould&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;a post about the &lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2009/04/gawker-headquarters-seating-chart"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Gawker&lt;/i&gt; office floorplan&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;and pithy news items from Balk and Sicha. "People were expecting something that was almost &lt;i&gt;Gawker&lt;/i&gt; 2.0," says &lt;em&gt;Nieman Lab&lt;/em&gt;’s Justin Ellis. "Instead it was something smaller and focused on the writing, where people can write about the stuff they’re passionate or super nerdy about." Insofar as the site had any kind of founding principle, it was that writers should only write about things they care about and not waste readers’ time. Its motto was "Be Less Stupid." Would it make readers smarter? &lt;a href="http://wayback.archive-it.org/all/20091130054740/http://www.vanityfair.com/online/culture/2009/04/21/blog-founders-plea-stay-away-stupid-people.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/em&gt; asked&lt;/a&gt; Sicha at the time. "I realized that we just don’t really want any stupid people reading it — which sounds mean, but they have plenty of reading material already," Sicha said. "I want to disinvite them."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balk did most of the writing, posting about&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/slug/bears"&gt;bears&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/slug/knifecrime-island"&gt;English knife crime&lt;/a&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.theawl.com/2010/11/there-is-a-light-that-always-goes-out"&gt;despair&lt;/a&gt;. His voice, unremittingly bleak to the point of comedy, with barbs hidden in the URL, alt-text, and tags, helped establish &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; as a place where writers could experiment. Sicha chimed in with items on New York plus whatever else caught his eye, and edited pieces from friends, many of them writers who lacked places to publish during the recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the fall of 2010, the company began to find its financial footing. They’d launched &lt;em&gt;Splitsider&lt;/em&gt; and were working with Edith Zimmerman to start &lt;em&gt;The Hairpin&lt;/em&gt;. David Cho had made a deal with Federated Media to run ads on the site, and money started to come in. Taking a cue from magazine advertorials, they’d also begun running sponsored content and native ads. "I think &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; was too small to get a lot of credit for it, but it was one of the first places to do it," Cho says. Sicha’s first paycheck &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/10/25/business/media/25carr.html?_r=0"&gt;warranted a column&lt;/a&gt; by the late David Carr, who joked that if you were going to launch a site, you’d look at everything &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; did — its hard-to-pronounce name, its eclectic mix of content, its literate but minuscule audience — and do the exact opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="The Awl Office" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vOmHs23_hU3ygoxWAteNPjA43WA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3857112/06.22.15_The_Verge__The_Awl_0033.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; sites &lt;/strong&gt;are run out of two rooms above a bodega in Brooklyn. It feels more like an apartment than an office, with everyone seated at desks crammed into one room, and occasionally retreating to the sofa next door for meetings. When I visited in May, the mood was relaxed and collegial: the band Destroyer played quietly over speakers, and Sicha, his shoes off and his feet propped on the desk, was going through a freelance budget. Buchanan and Herrman discussed Tom Scocca’s review of the previous day’s weather. Actual awls served as hazardous-looking paperweights among the seltzer cans and books scattered across the desks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just 13 people work at The Awl&amp;nbsp;Network, but it draws on a large reservoir of freelance talent. Writing for &lt;i&gt;The Awl &lt;/i&gt;isn’t lucrative, but writers have a lot of freedom, and the sites’ popularity among editors means it’s a good place to get noticed. Many writers have passed through and gone on to book deals or jobs at &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;New York Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt;, and elsewhere. Maria Bustillos, who now writes for &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; and other outlets, got her start when Sicha turned her emailed rant about &lt;em&gt;Avatar&lt;/em&gt; into a post. More recently, Jazmine Hughes went from co-editing &lt;em&gt;The Hairpin&lt;/em&gt; to editing at &lt;em&gt;The New York Times Magazine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is going to be gross because it’s so sincere," says&lt;i&gt; &lt;a href="http://the-toast.net/"&gt;The Toast’s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Mallory Ortberg, "but &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; is truly the best thing that ever happened to me." Her book, &lt;i&gt;Texts from Jane Eyre&lt;/i&gt;, began as a &lt;em&gt;Hairpin&lt;/em&gt; series that was inspired by a comment left on an &lt;em&gt;Awl&lt;/em&gt; story by her future &lt;em&gt;Toast&lt;/em&gt; co-editor Nicole Cliffe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Haley Mlotek" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/74nyMobDzofE6w2XcFWXuwFXzQA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3857198/06.22.15_The_Verge__The_Awl_0038.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: right; max-width: 98%;" class="caption"&gt;The Hairpin editor Haley Mlotek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sicha and Balk take a laissez-faire approach to running the network. "He’s always like, 'We are a confederation, you are your own state,'" &lt;em&gt;The Billfold&lt;/em&gt;’s Mike Dang says of Sicha. Balk is something like the editorial director, meeting with editors once a week about what’s coming up. Sicha is a mix of CFO and floating adviser. Jazmine Hughes describes him as the company’s cool aunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sicha has a rare ability to float above the online scrum that burns many writers out, and he’s instilled a similar ethos at the company. Ortberg compares him to Tom Bombadil, the friendly magical being from &lt;em&gt;Lord of The Rings&lt;/em&gt; who’s immune to the ring’s warping power. "A lot of folks who work in media are like, 'God, I have to carry the ring. Doesn’t this suck?' We all have to have the same fights. Tom Bombadil is… kind of untouched by all of it. He puts on the ring and doesn’t care. He’s just leaping around the woods merrily being like, ‘I own myself. I own these woods. No one can harm me.’ That to me is kind of Choire. He will choose what parts of the conversation he’s going to engage in, and he’ll choose how to talk about it, but you can’t make him do it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;"Sicha's just leaping around the woods merrily being like, ‘I own myself. I own these woods. No one can harm me.’"&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of Sicha and Balk’s advice involves encouraging editors to do what they want and ignore traffic. "Hot takes are epidemic," Sicha says, referring to hasty opinion pieces spun up to harness the inertia of a viral story. "Nobody should ever have to write X posts a day. That’s when you end up writing something you regret. You become someone else’s hot take."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dang and &lt;em&gt;The Hairpin&lt;/em&gt;’s Haley Mlotek say that Balk never encourages them to recreate past successes, simply shrugging and saying that you never know what hits. (One of &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt;’s most successful posts is Balk’s "&lt;a href="http://www.theawl.com/2009/11/how-to-cook-a-fucking-steak"&gt;How to Cook a Fucking Steak&lt;/a&gt;,"&amp;nbsp;which poked fun at the site’s sometimes precious food writing, but with righteous indignation that gets recurring traction on Facebook.) Sicha recently changed the password to the traffic-tracking app Chartbeat without telling anyone, then briefly forgot it. Most editors have it back now, though Buchanan and Herrman say they check it mostly to confirm the site isn’t dying. They both say one of the biggest luxuries of working there is being able to choose what they write about. "So many sites feel like they have to cover everything," Buchanan says. "We get to ignore most of it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By staying aloof from the content cycle, they’ve succeeded in creating a series of publications with coherent identities and distinct sensibilities. Those traits can be hard to maintain today, when stories are encountered alone and out of context on social platforms, and when there are huge incentives for covering viral stories that lie outside of a publication’s wheelhouse. &lt;em&gt;Gawker&lt;/em&gt;’s Denton lamented Facebook’s distorting effect in a &lt;a href="http://nick.kinja.com/back-to-blogging-1669401481"&gt;memo at the end of last year&lt;/a&gt;, saying that they’d become "slaves to the Facebook algorithm," and declaring a return to blogging. At &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt;, Sicha and Balk have tried to maintain that spirit since the beginning, building a network of sites unified by tone, with in-jokes and Easter eggs for longtime readers. It also means they’ve chosen to stay small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Matt laughing The Awl" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vFUc30ZZDOjt-sj42PawPqwPgUI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3857204/06.22.15_The_Verge__The_Awl_0086.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt;’s Jonah Peretti compares the site to an indie band. "It’s them saying, 'I don’t want to get that big, I want to stay true to my original rootedness in the music or this particular kind of art we’re making.' I’ve always seen [media] more like hip-hop, where you don’t sell out, you blow up. But there will always be a stage for certain indie rock sites that are about creating the in-group that has a certain aesthetic and special inside knowledge."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the economics of online advertising favor scale, and &lt;i&gt;The Awl &lt;/i&gt;is small: the site now gets a little over a million uniques a month, and the network usually gets 3 million, sometimes 4 million, Sicha says. (For comparison, BuzzFeed.com gets 190 million, according to Quantcast, which tends to be lower than internal Google Analytics numbers.) &lt;i&gt;The Awl&lt;/i&gt; makes a virtue out of its narrow audience when talking to advertisers, calling their readers "indielectuals," a term coined by former publisher John Shankman and which Sicha uses with an exaggerated shudder. According to Sicha, 29 percent of the site’s readers have graduate degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"It’s really a giant lesbian Australian socialized collective."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"By restricting audience size intentionally, you actually have a coherent audience to sell," Sicha says. "We actually argue a lot over what the maximum audience size is for each of the publications, and it’s not that big. I think &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; should never have more than 3 million readers a month. Anything beyond it and you’re dipping into people who can’t make sense of the content, who will be a distraction — it’s not for everyone else."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operating a site with narrow appeal means running extremely lean. Annual revenue is "in the very low seven figures," Sicha says, and at any given time the company has enough funds for one to four months’ worth of payroll in the bank. Instead of hiring writers, they partner with them to launch new sites, splitting revenue 50/50 between editors and the company, which handles the business and tech operations. Everyone owns a part of either their site or the company, Sicha says. "Basically nobody works for anyone here. It’s really a giant lesbian Australian socialized collective with capitalism in the mix in a really gross way."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With funds tight, new projects like the podcast tend to happen slowly. "Most places, you’d hire someone to make a podcast, but we all have 10 jobs," Sicha says. Herrman has been watching a lot of YouTube tutorials about podcast editing. "Either there’s going to be a podcast or the freelance checks are going to get cut," Sicha says. "There’s nobody else here." &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt;, he says, is "the littlest animal in the desert," inching along out of caution and scarce resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Awl Office Brooklyn" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_8Nj3ZBFfXmHza6cwEot_CIxJDc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3857104/06.22.15_The_Verge__The_Awl_0698.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the content apocalypse&lt;/strong&gt; comes, Herrman is cautiously optimistic that &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; will survive it. "We’ll be the cockroaches who don’t die but who are and will remain cockroaches," he says, laughing. The company was founded in a recession and to a large degree still runs like it’s in one. Over the years, it’s slowly built up a loyal readership large enough to keep it afloat, which alone is a feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where will &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; fit in the platform-dominated internet they’ve been writing about? "It doesn’t," Buchanan says. "Yeah, not really," Herrman agrees. "But then nothing fits in the new internet, nothing that isn’t literally an unincorporated part of the platform fits," he says. "&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; started when there was no obvious place for it. It is probably at its healthiest when there is no obvious place for it. We have functioned to some degree on platforms, but we would be very paranoid citizens who have survived some great upset and who remember."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"And who occasionally commit acts of sabotage," Buchanan adds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; exists for reasons other than expansion."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After stints at larger publications, Buchanan and Herrman have no plans to leave. "I love it here! There’s nowhere else like it," Herrman says when asked about longterm plans. "Also anybody in this industry who thinks they know what they're going to be doing in more than a couple years is mistaken." Asked about the future, Buchanan said he’d always planned to be dead by 35 and has nothing planned beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; exists for reasons other than expansion," Herrman says. "Maybe that’s why I’m so comfortable writing critically about companies that do seem to exist solely to grow, companies that function as pure economic instruments. &lt;em&gt;The Awl&lt;/em&gt; has a point for the people who started it. They want it to be a place where they and other people publish things that they like and don’t hate."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sicha is thinking more seriously about how to grow. "We’d like to do new sites, we’d like to be able have cash on hand," he says. Increasing readership by 30 percent would be "life changing" for the company, and he gets excited contemplating moving over to the business side and being "sort of mercenary and evil" about promoting the sites. "I like the idea of wholeheartedly crossing the church-state line and literally being like, ‘Hi, why aren’t you posting to Facebook? Here, tell me about your Pinterest strategy!’ Which is literally just something that no one would ever say in this company because, well, we just don’t care."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any growth would have to be "organic," he says. "I’m not saying game content, or do the stuff that always succeeds, or try to quantify it," he adds, slightly aghast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"But I do think that more than it ever has been, it’s important not to be cavalier about these things in the next six years." He pauses and leans back, looking at the ceiling. "Six years! Oh my god, I wish I was dead saying that." He’s never had a job this long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
  &lt;div class="chorus-snippet m-fishtank no-responsive-video"&gt;
  &lt;chorus-ad data-ad-slot="athena_features"&gt;&lt;/chorus-ad&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;





&lt;div id="credit"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;* *&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;*During the course of reporting this story, &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt;'s parent company, Vox Media, &lt;a href="http://blog.voxmedia.com/post/119972432417/vox-media-acquires-re-code"&gt;acquired Recode and the Code/Media conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: The Code/Media conference was hosted in February, not March, as previously stated. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clarification: The introduction was updated to include the fact that David Cho was also a co-founder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photography by &lt;a href="http://alexwelshphoto.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Alex Welsh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mvzelenks" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Zelenko&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/users/nilaypatel"&gt;Nilay Patel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/9/8908279/the-awl-profile-choire-sicha-john-herrman-matt-buchanan"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/9/8908279/the-awl-profile-choire-sicha-john-herrman-matt-buchanan</id>
    <author>
      <name>Josh Dzieza</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-06-25T10:00:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-25T10:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mary Barra is ready for the future</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nfp4ixng-ENLCHm4KrLJyKuB7vs=/186x0:2211x1350/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46611464/barra-fp-lead-4.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;After dealing with the past, GM's CEO wants to talk about what's next&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Barra lead" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dFykgDH6fnzAV9WhtPBR2xDdLDk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3821008/marry_barra_6172015_3.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Mary Barra is ready for the future&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;After dealing with the past, GM's CEO wants to talk about what's next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By Chris Ziegler&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mary Barra, a Stanford graduate, engineer, and three-decade veteran of General Motors,&lt;/strong&gt; was just 77 days into her new job as the company’s Chief Executive Officer when she was summoned to testify before Congress. A lingering ignition problem was affecting millions of GM vehicles, and had been tied to 13 deaths. It would be the first of several agonizing appearances for Barra in Washington, as representatives peeled back layer after layer of missed opportunities to mitigate one of the biggest safety disasters in modern automotive history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The massive waves of recalls had been brewing for years, long before Barra took the helm, but it came to a head while the paint was still drying in her Renaissance Center office. She had to play the hand she’d been dealt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way out — both for Barra and for GM — was to accept responsibility and make an  exceptionally convincing promise that a similar debacle could never happen again. To that end, she told lawmakers of the firings she’d swiftly overseen, the appointment of a vice president of global safety, and deep-rooted cultural shifts she was enacting inside the company. "I know some of you are wondering about my commitment to solve the deep underlying cultural problems uncovered in this report," Barra told lawmakers last June, referring to a damning report on the botched recalls delivered to GM’s board by former US attorney Anton Valukas. "The answer is I will not rest until these problems are resolved. As I told our employees, I am not afraid of the truth. And I am not going to accept business as usual at GM."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"I am not afraid of the truth. And I am not going to accept business as usual at GM."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, a year later, the crisis mode is behind her and Barra finally sounds able to look forward. And her forward-looking GM is a fascinating one: there’s the promise of the Chevy Bolt, a Tesla-fighting $30,000 electric car that the company says will get around 200 miles on a charge (in talking about going up against Tesla, she tells me that Chevrolet’s EVs are "designed for everyone, not just the elite"); the second-generation Volt is just months away from hitting dealerships; and the latest Corvette Z06 is the most exciting American performance car in ages (the forthcoming Ford GT notwithstanding). And all of this is happening amidst a sea change in the way drivers — especially smartphone-addled younger drivers — expect to interact with their cars and the world around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first on General Motors’ agenda is the redesigned Cruze, a small, global vehicle designed to appeal to that very same set of young, tech-native drivers. To call it a critical launch is an understatement: last month, GM sold more Cruzes in the US than it did all Buick models combined. Ahead of the new Cruze’s introduction, last week I sat down with Barra in New York City’s SoHo neighborhood for a wide-ranging interview about the company’s present and future — particularly around electrification and the advent of the connected car. The news of the day, the Cruze, seemed like a good way to kick things off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The interview has been edited for clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Barra Cruze" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-F5K6jYi7no-1L7xv-rGrt5t9wc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3821540/ChevyCruzeReveal02.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;Barra announces the Cruze in Detroit on June 24th. (GM)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris Ziegler: I think the Cruze is a good place to start.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary Barra: The Cruze is very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s a big launch for you. And it’s a global vehicle, right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, right. And if you look at the first-generation Cruze, it was really where I think General Motors had a serious contender in that segment. Now [we’re] really working and understanding the customer, taking it to the next level. When you look at the connectivity that we have in that vehicle, the safety features we have in the vehicle, I think it’s very important because the car sells globally in significant volumes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Those safety features are standard?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard features. Generally, you’ve got to look to a premium or a luxury brand, and clearly in the compact space, [the Cruze is] leading from a safety perspective. And then what we’re doing with connectivity, we have entries out there — you’ve probably critiqued them and you know where they can improve. But [we’re] looking at taking that to the next level, really understanding what the customer wants. And whether they have an Apple or an Android, to me, the real opportunity we have — and we’re just starting to scratch the surface — [is that] there’s so much information available in the car that we can marry with outside data to really provide value for the customer, make their life easier, make their life more convenient, provide services they didn’t know existed. So I think you’ll see us doing that as we go forward, and it’s really that integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know we’re all addicted to our smartphones, and I’ll say, if I forget my smartphone, I go home and get it. And so understanding how to integrate that technology into the driving experience, both the front seat and the passenger seat and the back seat, I think is very important. So I think you’ll see how we’re doing that. But it’s also focused on what the customer wants — their phone works quite well, so why wouldn’t we enable them to use certain functions, whether it’s their music or whatever? But then, like I said, where I think we’re going to surprise and delight with everything else we can do — some [functions] through the phone, but some through the unique system in the car to really provide value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you say the unique system in the car, that could be Cadillac CUE, or…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, or Chevy MyLink. And so you’ll see more things as we go forward we’ll be able to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think it’s very interesting that you’re putting features that were considered really high-tech even five years ago into the whole lineup, all the way down to the Spark. But historically, technology has been a differentiator for the premium segment. So, do you maintain that distinction between technology in, say, an ATS or CTS or CT6 versus the technology that’s going into a Spark? How? Even the Spark — once you add Android Auto and CarPlay to the car, it becomes a very high-tech rolling gadget.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"I know we’re all addicted to our smartphones... if I forget my smartphone, I go home and get it."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right. And I think what we’re trying to do, especially if you look at Chevy, we’re trying to make technology that’s going to benefit everyone, available to everyone — not just make certain technologies that are only for the elite. It’s really the whole democratization of technology. So when you look at Chevy’s brand promise — its value, its safety, its "wow" features — we’re looking by segment at what’s important to that customer and then making sure we put that technology in that vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still special things that we’re going to have for a luxury brand like our Cadillac brand or in some cases even Buick — where it may take it to the next level. It may be something that the customer can buy [as] an option that really is a premium from not only the cost perspective of putting it into the vehicle, but again, something that customers are willing to pay for added convenience. Or when you look at V2V [vehicle-to-vehicle] communications, we’ll have that. And the Super Cruise technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some technologies, to your point, you do put on luxury and then you learn customer acceptance and then you scale it across. One of the benefits General Motors has is tremendous scale. A lot of the features you’ll see us putting standard on the Cruze are features that we know customers are going to love. Some of the technologies, once you have [them] in a car, you’re like, "Wait! Why isn’t this happening? Why isn’t it warning me about this, or making sure I don’t do that in this circumstance?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So again, I think it’s understanding that customer, but leveraging the scale that General Motors had, the learning we’ve had, and putting those as standard. One of the clear things we want to make sure we differentiate ourselves on is being the safety leader. And that’s not only how we design the car from a crash-rating perspective, but the features we can put in [it] to make sure people are safe as they drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="CarPlay Chevy" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oGFLqd56vQTPSwtoxQgs009OVPI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3731030/chevywm7_2040.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;GM is rolling out CarPlay and Android Auto in a wide variety of models starting this year.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So you mentioned &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/1/10/5293892/automakers-want-to-see-through-walls-in-the-name-of-safety"&gt;V2V&lt;/a&gt;, which is obviously a safety feature. I got a demo of that a couple years ago at CES and was really blown away by what that could mean for vehicle safety. Is the plan to push that as rapidly as possible throughout the line? I know you’re debuting that on Cadillac, but what is the plan for V2V?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that when we start, it’s to learn; it’s to put it into the vehicle. To have V2V and I2I [infrastructure-to-infrastructure] really work, it’s an investment. I mean, you can do a lot [of testing] in the lab, [but] it’s [not] until you can get the technology into the market, into customers’ hands, you see the benefits, you see how you can leverage. Like we’ve seen with almost any technology, you can do so much more than you initially think. So [to] get the technology in the vehicle and learn, that’ll help guide the direction of where we take it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, looking at what’s happening in the entire landscape, the regulatory landscape: we demoed that technology to regulators around the globe so they understand where we’re headed. But I think it’s another step. I know a lot of people are making predictions [that] we’ll have autonomous vehicles here or there. Frankly, when I look at it, we have the technology to do autonomous vehicles right now. There [are so many things] along the way that we need to do, and one of the most important is customer acceptance. So to me, it’s about intelligent driving systems, and it’s about making sure that when [customers] think of the new Cruze, the features that make them safer, and then taking them on that journey. I mean, when you get to a point… I don’t know if you’ve had the opportunity to drive Super Cruise…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not yet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a person like yourself who’s driven for a few years at least, it’s a little eerie to take your hands off the wheel. So I think what’s very important is to make sure we take customers and drivers along with us, because it’ll be a journey of assisting all, making it safer on the way to full autonomous, which I think will vary in different countries, in different areas. But I think getting out there, learning, being first to get the technology into the marketplace is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wonder if it’s a matter of education versus a matter of a generational shift in the way you think about driving. Self-driving is a great example, because I’ve had a chance to sit in a few cars that are autonomous, and you’re right — you get in, and it’s like, "Whoa! Why is the car moving?" Is it something that’s going to click for people below a certain age, and not click for anyone above that age?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with most technologies, there will be the early adopters. Think about my parents as an example — they passed away about a decade ago, but they never [used] a bank machine. I don’t know if any of us would live without a bank machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;"We have the technology to do autonomous vehicles right now."&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think there will always be some generational comfort, but [with] autonomous — or like I like to call it, intelligent driving systems — I think it’s even a step more, because there’s just more of an aspect of trust that you’ve got to establish. And that’s why I think it’ll happen over time, as you build that [trust]. Because it’s trust in the specific technology, and it’s trust in the vehicle manufacturer and how they’ve integrated it into the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, the whole issue is how is it going to interface and integrate into the environment. Think of the streets of New York —  the jogger that runs out, or the dog, all the things that aren’t in a laboratory environment. More so than trusting your bank to put in that little plastic card, [the challenge] is going to be really understanding the technology enough that you trust it with what could be, in some cases, life-threatening situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearly regulation is a sticking point for a paradigm shift as big as intelligent driving. To what degree is GM involved in rule-making and helping governments around the world be at the leading edge of that, versus a rule comes in and you say, okay, that’s the law of the land?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we try to be very active. And, you know, [in] this country as well as many other countries, also with the Society of Automotive Engineers — it’s a great place for OEMs to come together and say, okay, what’s the best way to do it? Because we can all figure out a pretty good way, but if we all do it together, there’s a greater good. So we’re very active — in many cases, we lead the councils in the Society of Automotive Engineers. We regularly [talk to] regulators to say, "Okay, here’s what we’re doing, here’s how we see it." Do you see it a different way, or can we share this with you so you have the same experience that we have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we try to be very involved, because at the end of the day, they are our regulators and they have a very important role. But there [are] some places where we can work together and advance the industry. When you look at what most regulations are written for, it’s for people to be safer. If we can help advance that, we will do that, and I think we demonstrated a couple different technologies local to the US to NHTSA so they understand where we’re working and [we've] taken their feedback and we’ll continue to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NHTSA seems pretty proactive about trying to get ahead of the regulatory framework for some of this stuff, but there’s still a long road ahead. Are you concerned that at end of the day, that’s going to be [the bottleneck]? What is the long tail for rolling this stuff out?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, that’s a good question. I actually think the regulators are trying to move very quickly with industry, and partner with them —  in some cases lead and in some cases say, okay, here’s what we can do, let’s get that quickly. I think in some cases there are going to be legal issues that have to be addressed. I attended a conference on intelligent driving systems, and the insurance industry — it’s very clear that their first [concern is]…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The liability.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"Any time you have a dramatic shift, [...] everyone tries to advance their personal position."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly. How does that change in a way that doesn’t transfer responsibility to someone who is not accepting, not aware, or someone who doesn’t make sense? It’s almost like you’ve got to take the whole ecosystem and adapt to the technology what it can do, and therefore be fair about it. And obviously, any time you have a dramatic shift, and you have multiple parties involved, everyone tries to advance their personal position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why I think it’s so important that we look at this from the customer perspective. If you step back and say, "Hey, this is about safer driving, it’s about less congestion, it’s about safety, it’s about reducing fatalities and injuries on the road, that’s where we’re going, it’s the right place." Now, how do we all move there together and adjust the system so it’ll have a better outcome for everybody, [while] making sure that one group or one faction doesn’t try to, you know, over-index at the detriment of what the end goal is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Bolt prototype" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/um4ItmK0gKoqySFj32rz6wLJU1s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3821546/ChevyBoltEVCamo02.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;A camouflaged prototype Bolt EV gets shaken down on GM's Milford, Michigan test track. (GM)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s keep pushing on the next generation [of drivers]. Future drivers are smartphone-native and internet-native. And there are certain expectations that come with that. Over the next five to 10 years, car buyers are certainly going to expect a baseline of tech features that didn’t even exist five years ago. CarPlay and Android Auto are a good example.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think you’re absolutely right, and I think it’s a huge opportunity. That’s why at GM, and specifically Chevrolet, we’re putting so much focus not just on new technology, but technologies that really add value for the customer’s in-vehicle experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Chevy’s probably [targeting a younger audience] than, say, Cadillac, for obvious reasons.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it’s our brand that provides tremendous value, so for a lot of people it’s their first vehicle. But I can tell you I know people who wouldn’t buy anything but a Chevrolet. Because, again, the loyalty and the car’s been there, delivered for them. If you haven’t, you should drive the Impala. The Chevrolet Impala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"When you look at the Bolt EV, [it’s] truly a breakthrough to say we’re going to go 200 miles without a charge."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yeah, I’ve driven the Impala; it’s a great car. [&lt;em&gt;This is true; I drove a review vehicle some time ago, and it’s pretty fantastic for a large sedan. -Ed.&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, when you look at the value in that car. So I think we’ll continue to look at what technology we can put in the vehicle, whether it’s integrating from a connectivity perspective, or electrification when you look at the next-generation Volt and the Bolt EV. Look at gen-one Volt to gen-two Volt, the amount of improvements we’ve made in the energy density, the efficiency of the battery. We did incremental improvement through the life of gen-one Volt, but in gen two, we’re taking another giant step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we listened to the customers. [Volt customers] are some of the most satisfied customers in the industry, not just for General Motors, but for the industry, [and we listened] to them. And then also looking at electrification — when you look at the Bolt EV, [it’s] truly a breakthrough to say we’re going to go 200 miles without a charge, and it’s going to be in that around $30,000 price range, really making sure that’s available to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaking of Volt and powertrain advancements, I don’t think anyone disagrees that fossil fuel is ultimately a dead end, right? It’s a question of when — 10 years or 100? Correct me if I’m wrong, but I would assume that GM shares that opinion, so the question is how quickly you can push technologies that aren’t just extended-range electric, but full electric like the Bolt across the range? Can you get them affordable enough? I know that Bolt is a part of that equation, but you have products like the [Corvette] Z06, which, considering what it is, is a very fuel-efficient vehicle. But long term, you’re going to have to investigate alternative powertrains for that. So how quickly can you push that through the range? And is that something you’re trying to do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely. We see electrification across Chevrolet and across the different portfolios having its place. I personally think the internal combustion engine, when you look at the improvements we’ve made [in] fuel efficiency and continue to do, I think the technology will tell us when certain changes [need to be] made. The battery technology, again, I reference how much improvement we’ve seen. When you start to build something, build it in scale, learn, you find ways to continuously improve and then leapfrog. We work with some of the preeminent battery suppliers. We already do our own battery assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we’ve got all that learning, and we’ll continue to push the envelope on what the range can be and the energy density of the battery — because it’s range, it’s the size, and it’s the cost. We’re pushing on all three, and continue to work both inside the company and with strategic partners to drive that. When you look at the Volt and the Bolt EV concept and the broad statement we made, it’s an area we want to lead. I think we’ve got some pretty good proof points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But by the same token, you also are staring down the barrel of much stricter federal emissions standards.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, absolutely. And that’s why I think you look at the technology, and [decide] what is the most efficient way. I believe the customer is extremely rational, and they’ll say, am I going to buy this internal combustion version? Am I going to buy light electrification? Am I going to buy a Volt? [It depends] on their use case, and they’re going to do the math. And, you know, assume a range of fuel prices. I think as long as we keep pushing on the electrification side of it, keep pushing that closer so the math works [and] they can make a rational choice, I think we’ll continue to push on the electrification and continue to have more and more sales and volume there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, one of the things we’ve learned on the Volt — the Volt’s been out since 2010 — [is that] there are still a lot of people who will say to me, "But what happens when the Volt’s battery dies?" And they don’t understand that there’s the extended range capability. So some of it is education as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But ultimately, the goal is to have a Bolt type of product, presumably? Right? I mean, long term? We just saw some new numbers come out that suggest that the recent drop in fuel prices has significantly increased the percentage of hybrid and EV buyers who are trading in for SUVs. Point taken about the consumer being rational, but maybe they’re hyper-rational where they’re making very localized decisions based on literally today’s fuel price, and today’s fuel price isn’t next year’s fuel price. So to what degree is GM responsible for telling the consumer that they need to move toward electrification versus them making their own choice?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think most customers in any industry don’t want to be told what to do. I think what our job is, and what we work really hard on, and we want to lead, and again, I think we have proof points on the board, is to continue to put electrification solutions, hybrids… I mean, we even have a partnership on fuel cells. So to continue to push on all aspects, how do we improve the efficiency and reduce any impact to the environment? We’re going to continue to push on all of those, and again, that’s an area we want to lead in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;"I think most customers in any industry don’t want to be told what to do."&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you look at the Spark EV that we have out right now, the [next-generation] Volt, we’ve had electrification in some vehicles that customers said, "Eh, not that interested." But we continue to put it out, learn, and even when you have a product with electrification that maybe wasn’t the success that you thought it was in the marketplace, you really learn. It’s something where we have to point to all the vehicles we already had in market that have had electrification, because that’s all built our learning and said okay, well, it didn’t work there, but we used that technology and that allowed us to leapfrog and move quickly here. We’re committed to making sure we have the most efficient solutions across the board, and then we’re not forcing the customer to do something. My view is always, how much choice can I give them that’s also regulatory compliant or beyond?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Chevrolet Bolt" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RZaY8roTH_mvv3XQSAKVMV08qDg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/2924984/chevy-naias-2015-104-1020.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;The concept version of the Bolt debuted at the North American International Auto Show earlier this year.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, blue sky, I imagine this is something you’ve thought about: at the end of the decade, what percentage of GM’s sales are electrified?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, any time anybody’s tried to make a prediction, they’ve been wrong, including heads of state! I don’t want to guess at that. But what I will tell you is we’ve also built tremendous flexibility. It’s one of the reasons we have our own battery assembly plant that’s configured to not only do light electrification but also full electrification — to make sure that we can quickly respond to the customer demands. And continue to look across a wide range of vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s talk about the batteries for a second. You mentioned that you assemble them yourself. But the cells themselves — are you running into scale constraints? Tesla obviously is shouting from every mountaintop that scale is a problem, Gigafactory is a thing. Would you buy batteries from Tesla? Or maybe more to the point, would you build your own cells?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of different areas where we’re doing R&amp;D on our own, where we’re working with key suppliers, where we’re partnering with universities. We’re going to continue to do that. So much for me from a battery perspective is, you can get so far with the cost and the energy density, but what’s the next breakthrough? I mean, a few years back, no one was touting that they were going to [have] the efficiency that we’re going to do [with] the Chevrolet Bolt EV, you know, that kind of battery capability. There’s going to be much more to be done and there will be more breakthroughs in battery technology to truly get to a wide fleet offering. When you look at the scale that we have — we work with some pretty important and significant battery makers already. We’ll continue to do that, along with, like I said, from startups to well-established battery companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Battery companies like] LG Chem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;"I’ll never say never to anything."&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah. We’re already doing that, we have our own projects with universities. Electrification will be key in China, [and] we have SAIC who’s our partner there. Another opportunity for scale. So I think we’ve got the flexibility. I’ll never say never to anything, but when I look at where it’s going, to me, the chemistry and the breakthroughs are so important, and that’s where we’re really focusing. Because frankly, then, to get it made is not usually… that’s not the biggest challenge that I’ve seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oh, really?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we did the Bolt and Volt development, and again, that’s [the battery manufacturers’] major business, they know how to do that. We made the decision to assemble just because we wanted to have the flexibility to really optimize it into the vehicle, and that’s where we, you know, as we were kind of doing this new area, I was involved in that space. We made the decision of where we’re going to, what we’re going to do in-house versus not, because what we need to control to have the best integration, best quality, best performance. If something changes, we’ll continue to re-evaluate that. But [we have] pretty strong partners we work with right now on the actual cell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This goes back to younger buyers and drivers — again, super smartphone-native — are used to configurability, and "hacking" their phone to do what they want it to do. What is GM’s stance on very deep customization of the vehicle, and to what extent can a car become like a giant smartphone? Can enthusiasts hack their car? I think of the Woodward Dream Cruise type of folks who are really going deep on their cars from the ’60s and ’70s, and customizing them and doing what they want with them. How does that translate into a 21st-century vehicle, and to what extent are you keeping the electronics of the car locked down? Because I think of a car buyer today, their idea of customizing their vehicle is much more high-tech than it was 30 or 40 years ago.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think if you look at a Cadillac CUE or look at the new Corvette and the amount of customization you can do of what you’re seeing here and what you’re seeing on the display, it’s incredible. We also have an obligation. So when you kept saying "hack," I hate the word "hack." That’s what I worry about! So we’ve gotta strike that balance of how much configurability can we have that we allow the customer to do, but then how do we do that in an environment that still doesn’t let someone who has less honorable goals in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safety is my overriding priority, because unlike a lot of other things that can get hacked, they don’t have necessarily deadly consequences. So we’re going to want to provide as much customization and flexibility for the consumer [as we can], but the foundation will be that it’s safe. And I actually think that the customer will respect that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;"I hate the word ‘hack.’ That’s what I worry about!"&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want something that, yeah, you can get in and change, but so can someone else too easily? No, you want to make sure you’ve got a system that you can make be exactly what you want but it’s going to operate that way and you can trust it. Because think about the relationship we have with our vehicles. You’ve got to be able to trust it. And so, to me, we place a high importance on that, we’ve invested greatly in it, we have expertise in-house, and we consult with some of the best people around the globe to make sure. Because it’s something that is evolving at lightning speed, and we want to make sure that we provide that balance. And frankly, I’ve been in the industry my whole life, and when you look at it, I think there’s so much we can allow people to do that I think we can strike a happy chord there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is building off something that you said at Code Conference — you mentioned that you see very tight integration between the car systems and Android Auto and CarPlay. You think that that’s sort of the way it’s going, versus ceding control of the dashboard to Google and Apple. But I’m wondering if you can expand on that a bit, because really what you’re asking customers to do is deal with two user interfaces, right? And maybe that’s not the most user-friendly way to do it. So, looking forward five or 10 years, as you go into the second and third generations of these systems, explain what you mean by "integration."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as I see it down the road, your customer likes to do what they can do on their phone because it’s easy. Right now, we’re allowing people to bring their phones and then have what they do easily and bring that into the vehicle. But there is so much more that we can to do integrate to provide value for the customer with the vehicle, that my vision is there’s no ceding of anything here. But my clear vision is there’ll come a point in time where intuitive is intuitive, and if you can do it and have access, and the stuff you need from there is there and it’s integrated, there’s so much we can provide. People don’t even really think about it yet. Same way, until you had your first app, and now, how many apps do you have? Think about it that way. So this first generation, yeah, there’s some switching back and forth, but my vision is we go forward, we’re going to welcome a variety of phones, seamless for the customer, but very well integrated for the customer by us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="credit"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;* *&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portrait photography by Nancy Borowick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited by Michael Zelenko&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/25/8834151/gm-ceo-mary-barra-interview-2015"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/25/8834151/gm-ceo-mary-barra-interview-2015</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Ziegler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-06-24T10:06:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-24T10:06:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>What's the deal with translating Seinfeld</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/72_da5fXJcI9atcBlD6Wjy2_kBQ=/27x0:331x203/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46598490/slide1_360.0.0.png" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like so many&lt;/strong&gt; of Jerry Seinfeld’s girlfriends on &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld,&lt;/em&gt; Dolores was TV-beautiful, with glossy, reddish-blond hair, big blue eyes, full lips, and impeccable bone structure. Most of Jerry’s girlfriends brought with them a joke about the trials of dating and/or the self-centeredness of Jerry’s character, and Dolores was no exception: Jerry very much wanted to sleep with her, but he hadn’t asked her name when they met, and by the time they went out, he was too embarrassed to admit he didn’t know it. He surreptitiously searched her purse for an ID, but came up short. He asked friends to introduce themselves to her, hoping she would introduce herself back; she didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="seinfeld" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mLmjisKFNgjxISk-2Wu8NpbCyJQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3812920/seinfeld_lead_update.0.gif"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;section class="lede"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Translator Sabine Sebastian tried to bring Seinfeld to Germans, yada yada yada, it flopped&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By Jennifer Armstrong&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like so many&lt;/strong&gt; of Jerry Seinfeld’s girlfriends on &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld,&lt;/em&gt; Dolores was TV-beautiful, with glossy, reddish-blond hair, big blue eyes, full lips, and impeccable bone structure. Most of Jerry’s girlfriends brought with them a joke about the trials of dating and/or the self-centeredness of Jerry’s character, and Dolores was no exception: Jerry very much wanted to sleep with her, but he hadn’t asked her name when they met, and by the time they went out, he was too embarrassed to admit he didn’t know it. He surreptitiously searched her purse for an ID, but came up short. He asked friends to introduce themselves to her, hoping she would introduce herself back; she didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had only one clue to go on: she’d told him that as a child, she was teased for her name: "What do you expect when your name rhymes with a part of the female anatomy?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerry, George, and Kramer worked at the the puzzle: Celeste? Aretha? Bovary? Mulva?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not until she walked out on Jerry, disgusted that he didn’t know her name, that it came to him: Dolores!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed//-LW0RikQ3mc"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;"The Junior Mint," &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld's 60th episode, featured Dolores.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dolores left Jerry's life when that episode aired on March 18th, 1993. Two years later, Dolores became Sabine Sebastian's headache. Tasked with translating all 180 half-hour episodes of &lt;i&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/i&gt; into German for dubbing and broadcast overseas, Sebastian ran into major roadblocks in bringing what she thought was one of the funniest shows she’d ever seen to her countrymen and women. The hit American sitcom so often relied on word-based humor, American customs, and Jewish references. The first two of these meant Sebastian had to go far beyond literal translation; and the latter was an ongoing sore point between her and the editor she was working with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;q&gt;Aretha? Bovary? Mulva?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dolores represented one of the toughest puzzles Sabine had encountered: "Dolores" doesn’t rhyme with any German words for a body part, and a fabricated name would detract from the joke. Just because Jerry’s friends guessed "Bovary" as a legitimate name option in English didn’t mean she could throw any old name around in German.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was just another day in the life of a translator tackling &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld.&lt;/em&gt; But it was a particularly vexing one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More so than the average American sitcom, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; has had difficulty reaching global audiences. While it’s popular in Latin America, it hasn’t been widely accepted in Germany, France, Italy, and the Netherlands. Two decades after it went off the air, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; remains relevant to American audiences — thanks in part to omnipresent syndicated reruns — but in much of Europe it is considered a cult hit, and commonly relegated to deep-late-night time slots. Its humor, it seems, is just too complicated, too cultural and word-based, to make for easy translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the show now finally coming to streaming services for the first time this month, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; had another shot at gaining a worldwide audience. But the fact that today it &lt;a href="http://www.hulu.com/seinfeld"&gt;began streaming on Hulu&lt;/a&gt;, not Netflix, is telling: Netflix is available across dozens of countries around the world — Hulu is only available in the United States and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="george" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BwvkAfhQ9iVr0yCGedSEbg3N5-s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3816704/george_003.0.gif"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Are those woman’s breasts real? How long can one go without masturbating?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jokes are the hardest&lt;/strong&gt; things to translate into another language, another culture, another world. A good script for dubbing an American sitcom for foreign consumption does more than literally translate. It manages to convey the same meaning, the same feeling, the same story — the same direct hit to the lower frontal lobes of the brain that produces a laugh, even though those frontal lobes are steeped in a completely different cultural brew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because of &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;’s unique approach to comedy, it poses special translation problems. In one &lt;a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=YbyoAwAAQBAJ&amp;q=radboud#v=snippet&amp;q=radboud&amp;f=false"&gt;Radboud University study&lt;/a&gt; of Dutch viewers’ reactions to &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;, viewers commonly reported being baffled by the show’s laugh track; the audience regularly missed the joke. Some of those who did laugh told researcher Elke Van Cassel that they were laughing only because the characters reminded them of Americans they knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; was, as the series famously dubbed itself, "a show about nothing": four self-centered New Yorkers making a dramatic showing of dealing with minor daily irritations and social faux pas. Can you hire a hitman to take out an annoying neighbor dog? Are those woman’s breasts real? How long can one go without masturbating? And do you care to make a bet on that answer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; debuted on NBC in 1989, it felt like an acquired taste, a cult hit at best. It didn’t offer the simple, linear humor of &lt;em&gt;The Cosby Show,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Roseanne,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Cheers&lt;/em&gt; — the most popular shows at the time. Instead, it relied on sophisticated linguistic humor; implication instead of explicitness (abstaining from masturbation is, for instance, being "master of your domain"); and deconstruction of the social norms of a very particular group of New Yorkers — unlikeable New Yorkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite NBC’s low expectations, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; grew into an unlikely sensation throughout its run in the ‘90s, partly by expressing the consumerist, narcissistic elements of the era. It lasted for nine years until Seinfeld voluntarily ended it (despite &lt;a href="http://edition.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/9712/26/seinfeld/"&gt;NBC offering him $5 million per episode&lt;/a&gt; to return for another season). And it made icons of its four central characters: uptight Jerry (Jerry Seinfeld), bumbling George (Jason Alexander), manic Kramer (Michael Richards), and smart-ass Elaine (Julia Louis-Dreyfus). In its final season, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; hit a peak, averaging 38 million viewers per episode. Its 1998 finale was one of the most anticipated, most watched, most passionately debated hours of American television of the last 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; deconstructed a very particular group of New Yorkers —  unlikeable New Yorkers&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even its closest cohort at the time, &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt; — which &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; co-creators Larry David and Jerry Seinfeld have often insisted "stole" its concept from them — couldn’t touch what made &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; unique. Yes, both shows centered on groups of young-ish, single friends in New York City. But where &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt; employed traditional A- and B-plot lines, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; zigged and zagged until bringing the most seemingly unrelated story elements together in a balletic denouement. Where &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt; exploited its touchy-feely relationships, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; avoided them at all costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This made &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; the rare TV show that was both innovative and wildly popular. It seemed poised for world domination as it entered the international syndication market. After all, as America goes, so goes the world. Right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="seinfeld" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c2BFqOqSwFzmGXr1gNSwkBOCZLY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3813152/spectacular.0.gif"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sabine Sebastian hoped so.&lt;/strong&gt; Sebastian — a jovial woman who resembles the actress Emma Thompson — works as a director, scriptwriter, and sometimes voice actor in Germany’s lip-synch dubbing business, bringing American movies and TV shows to her countrymen and women. She knows the dangers of direct translations, particularly when it comes to sitcoms. For every language-based joke that works easily — Elaine’s quest for "schwämmchen-würdig," or "spongeworthy," suitors was a one-to-one translation — many others don’t. Canadian translation company LingoStar, for instance, &lt;a href="http://www.lingo-star.com/do-successful-translations-of-our-favourite-sitcoms-exist/"&gt;cites&lt;/a&gt; a joke that had to be simplified in a &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt; episode in which Monica saw a woman’s huge engagement ring and cracked, "Oh my god, you can’t even see where the Titanic hit it." This was translated as, "Oh my, but it’s an iceberg."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The German voice actors soon became a united cast, as bonded as their American counterparts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian had done a lot of work for Brandtfilm, a Berlin company responsible for the dubbed German versions of American sitcoms such as &lt;em&gt;M*A*S*H&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Odd Couple.&lt;/em&gt; In 1995, they asked her to direct their newest project, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She loved the show. She’d appreciated its sarcastic wit since watching the very first episode, and she enjoyed the next-level humor it delivered as it grew ever more self-referential, nowhere better exemplified than in the episodes about the fictional sitcom &lt;em&gt;Jerry&lt;/em&gt;. She felt lucky to get the gig, and she knew that Brandtfilm was lucky to have her on it — these things always went better when the translator was a real fan. She wanted to help her fellow Germans appreciate &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; as much as she did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With her cast and crew, she plowed through the five seasons of the show that had already aired in the United States — she would record them all in succession, then tackle the show’s remaining seasons as they concluded in America. But things went off track soon, she later told me. She didn’t care much for the scripts she was getting from the dialogue book writers. They were translating too literally. Subtle word choices could make a difference, and she changed a lot of the scripts as she recorded. By the show’s eighth season, she finally took over all writing duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her main voice actors — Oliver Feld as Jerry, Traudel Haas as Elaine, Detlef Bierstedt as George, and K. Dieter Klebsch as Kramer — pitched in as well, refining lines as needed whenever they thought the translations weren’t funny enough. They soon became a united cast, as bonded as their American counterparts. (Years later, the team even reunited to reprise their roles in the German version of the &lt;em&gt;Curb Your Enthusiasm&lt;/em&gt; episodes in which the cast of &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; gets back together.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the actors got better at working together, they had more suggestions for improving the scripts. Often, Sebastian took entire scenes home to rework them overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to Dolores, of course, Sebastian had to work extra hard. Finally, she hit upon a distinctly German solution: she substituted Dolores (rhymes with "clitoris") with Uschi (rhymes with "muschi," slang for vagina). Uschi is a relatively common German name, short for Ursula. Perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="kramer" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jLGuBfxcjPW7FF-uqE7DrI3KGu0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3816808/kreamer_007.0.gif"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not all television&lt;/strong&gt; shows are dubbed for export — &amp;nbsp;some are subtitled, and some end up with both versions available. Then, it’s up to the channels that run them to choose a format for their audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s a clunkiness to dubbing that grates on American sensibilities&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.trans-that.com/Articles-about-translation-edit-and-content/dubbing-subtitles"&gt;According to Israel-based translation company Trans-That&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;among European countries, France, Germany, Italy, and Spain tend to opt for the more expensive option of dubbing, while smaller countries like Belgium, Switzerland, and the Netherlands prefer subtitles. Dubbing countries often have &lt;a href="http://www.1stoptr.com/admin/UpImage/Dubbing_vs_Subtitling.pdf"&gt;a long history with the practice&lt;/a&gt; that goes back to the beginnings of the film industry. In the 1930s, when many American films were being exported to Europe, the strong preference for dubbing &lt;a href="http://www.filmreference.com/encyclopedia/Criticism-Ideology/Dubbing-and-Subtitling-THE-DUBBING-AND-SUBTITLING-INDUSTRIES.html"&gt;grew out of nationalist concerns&lt;/a&gt; — preserving language meant preserving cultural identity. In these countries, entire industries developed around dubbing. Today, certain voice actors will specialize in playing specific American stars, to the point where audiences expect to hear their voice each time they go to see, say, a Tom Cruise movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from in certain genres like anime, American audiences rarely encounter dubbing. For one, Americans tend to consume American media; for another, there’s a clunkiness to dubbing that grates on American sensibilities. Both dubbing and translation have obvious advantages and disadvantages: in dubbing, the translation can be altered to fit the culture of the target audience; in subtitling, the original sound of the actors’ voices comes through, conveying meaning beyond language. Some viewers like reading the words; others hate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed//rziprdaE_SI"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cheers&lt;/span&gt;, renamed &lt;span&gt;Prost Helmut&lt;/span&gt;, appealed to German audiences in a way &lt;span&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/span&gt; never did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lip-synch dubbing, despite its ultimate benefits, can get very complicated. It’s not just that the lines may not translate directly — they also have to take just as long to say in both languages and approximate, to the best of their abilities, the lip movements of the original actors. That can pose an added challenge when translating from laconic languages like English into verbose languages like German. And &lt;i&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/i&gt; was already a very wordy show, making accurate translation that much more critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script-writing process for foreign translation is so elaborate that it’s a wonder even one episode gets done. Sebastian had to produce 180. With the American script in hand and a direct translation into German, Sebastian worked out lines that would transmit the humor and match the actors’ lip movements. She then spoke them into her laptop while watching the episode on loop. She could watch a sentence a hundred times over if necessary. Jump back, jump back, jump back again on the DVD. All day long, she watched lines, then yelled her best translations into the computer’s microphone. Because the spoken version was the priority, writing it down wouldn’t do. Sentence by sentence, phrase by phrase, she made &lt;i&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/i&gt; understandable to German speakers. When she finished, she’d send her spoken version to a transcriber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;Translating a single sitcom episode can take longer than an entire action movie&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of how dialogue-heavy sitcoms tend to be, translating a single episode can take longer than an entire action movie — that was doubly true for &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;. A lot of close-ups, which allowed viewers to see the actors’ mouth movements, complicated matters even further. The entire process for a 22-minute &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; episode took three work days, or about 18 hours total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while lip-syncing could be solved given enough time and patience, aligning cultural references often proved too difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seinfeld’s&lt;/em&gt; Jewish references posed a unique challenge: as Sebastian explained, "The Germans have a certain you-know-what with the Jewish." Her editor was worried about some of &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;’s Jewish jokes. "We better not say it like that," she remembered her editor saying, "because the Germans may be offended." She added later, recalling the incident to me, "They should be offended, in my understanding. They did it!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian appreciated &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;’s direct approach to Jewish history. She wanted to use jokes in direct translation, but the editor wouldn’t let her. She lost several battles. It was a fine line: Der Suppen-Nazi? Sure. Subtle reference to an uncle who survived a concentration camp? Not so fast. An entire episode based on George being mistaken for a neo-Nazi was problematic. So were references to the TV miniseries &lt;em&gt;Holocaust&lt;/em&gt; and the film &lt;em&gt;Schindler’s List.&lt;/em&gt; Take Elaine’s voiceover narration in "The Subway" episode when her train gets stuck: "We are in a cage. … Oh, I can't breathe, I feel faint. Take it easy, it'll start moving soon. Think about the people in the concentration camps, what they went through."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed//mhNc3oaEUUE"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Der Suppen-Nazi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, Sebastian triumphed in her conflicts with editors — the practicalities of the show demanded an authentic translation. In an early episode, one of Jerry’s comedy routines addresses the fact that Nazis in World War II movies had "like two separate ‘heils.' They had like the regular ‘heil,’ and then when they were around the offices, they had like this casual ‘heil.’" There was no way to avoid a faithful translation in that case: Seinfeld made the Hitler salute as he spoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Sebastian’s episodes started airing in 1996, they amassed a small, cult-level following in Germany. German TV programmers seemed confused about where it might play best: It moved from 6:50PM to 5:45AM to 11PM, then was canceled. It returned two years later at 1:10AM, then 6PM, then 11:45PM. As Dutch TV researcher Van Cassel noted in a study that examined &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;’s lack of traction with Dutch and German audiences, programmers’ "indecision seems to be more of a consequence than a cause of the lack of interest displayed by the viewers. Both Dutch and German networks did try broadcasting &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; at prime time at least once, but apparently the ratings did not increase."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Sarcasm and sophisticated, plot-based humor did not tend to appeal to large German audiences&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian didn’t believe her fellow Germans rejected &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; because the main character was Jewish. The dubbing issues contributed to watering down some of &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;’s humor, and she thought the show was "too intelligent" for German audiences. Sitcoms weren’t their thing, and they tended to enjoy more simple, straightforward shows like police drama &lt;em&gt;Alarm für Cobra 11&lt;/em&gt;, crime drama &lt;em&gt;Der letzte Zeuge&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Medicopter 117&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;ALF&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.avclub.com/article/big-in-japan-and-elsewhere-29-american-cultural-en-81933"&gt;was famously more popular in Germany than in America&lt;/a&gt; — the David Hasselhoff of sitcoms. &lt;em&gt;Who’s the Boss?&lt;/em&gt; was also a sensation. Sarcasm and sophisticated, plot-based humor did not tend to appeal to large audiences there. Sebastian also oversaw dubbing for the caustic British comedy &lt;em&gt;Absolutely Fabulous&lt;/em&gt; — it too flopped in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus in Germany,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; will likely continue rerunning in the early morning hours (3:45AM or 7:45AM on cable channel TNT Serie, depending on the day). Those who have continued to watch have been passionate enough to keep it around, bonding on internet message boards as they dissect Sebastian’s translation versus the original English, season after syndicated season. "I think the translation was the reason &lt;i&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/i&gt; never was a big hit in Germany," wrote German commenter Der Olli on &lt;a href="http://kenlevine.blogspot.com/2011/05/lost-in-translation.html"&gt;TV writer Ken Levine’s&lt;/a&gt; website. Another German commenter, Marco, defended the dubbing, citing a particularly clever substitution: "There was an episode where a teacher who [sic] (in the original version) pronounced George’s last name like &lt;em&gt;CantStandYa&lt;/em&gt;. The german version was slightly different where the teacher called George &lt;em&gt;Kotztanzo&lt;/em&gt;. The result is equally funny since both versions nail the point (the teacher disliking George and thus pronouncing his name like some sort of insult)."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o0tvfbMslSI"&gt;YouTube pages with clips of the show&lt;/a&gt;, the debates can be a little more direct. "In German, I do not like &lt;i&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/i&gt;," wrote one commenter. "In English, it’s my favorite show."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="newman" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E6tZlaJTe3dn_DIUPoT3E-s7fn4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3813124/newman_gif.0.gif"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The difficulties Sebastian&lt;/strong&gt; faced in bringing &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; to German speakers showed just how hard this particular show was to translate for non-American audiences. But even in England, &lt;i&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/i&gt; wasn’t a huge hit. It seems that among the only people watching it in late-night reruns — following it through constant scheduling shuffles and frequent pre-emptions for snooker tournaments — were British comedians. Writer-actor David Baddiel told &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2012/apr/30/after-seinfeld-jerry-sitcom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2012 that he remembered talking about the show with fellow comics at clubs in the ‘90s. Sam Bain, who co-wrote British hits &lt;em&gt;Peep Show&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Fresh Meat,&lt;/em&gt; cited &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;’s layered plotting and its signature move — bringing all the plot strands together with an absurdist twist — as the template for his shows. Graham Linehan, writer-director of &lt;em&gt;The IT Crowd&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Father Ted,&lt;/em&gt; said in the same piece that &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; was "the funniest show on TV. … Every time I write, I’m trying to write &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As television globalizes and cable options proliferate, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;’s cult status has allowed it to make a few new inroads into international markets. Despite early struggles in the Netherlands, &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; has found a passionate following on a Dutch version of the cable channel Comedy Central. And in 2013, French television revisited &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; for the first time in more than a decade; l’Enorme TV, a new cable channel dedicated to comedy, started rerunning it on Wednesday nights dubbed in French and on Saturday nights in English with subtitles. The network found that "any channel that wants to broadcast &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; must have an audience used to American life and standup culture," Julie Cantin, a spokeswoman for l’Enorme, told me. But according to her, anecdotal evidence on social media proves that "there are &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; fans in France."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;Perhaps &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; isn’t as full of "nothing" as Americans like to think&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, chances are that France will never have the same kind of lasting relationship with &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; that the United States does. Perhaps &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; isn’t as full of "nothing" as Americans like to think; or more precisely, it's full of a very American kind of nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that goes a long way toward explaining why US-focused Hulu was willing to shell out &lt;a href="http://variety.com/2015/tv/news/hulu-seinfeld-licensing-160-million-1201483537/"&gt;a reported $160 million&lt;/a&gt; for streaming rights, while internationally distributed Netflix dropped out of the bidding early. (Netflix did not respond to requests for comment.) Despite the powers of the internet, and the growing number of English speakers around the world, our ability to share pop culture across international waters — especially the nuances of comedy — remains limited by our ability to understand each other. And even when we speak the same language, our jokes may still not translate, or resonate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s to &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt;’s credit that it has a hard time crossing certain borders. The more sophisticated and innovative the humor, the harder it is to translate. In many of the countries where &lt;em&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/em&gt; remains a cult hit, the more traditional &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Cosby Show&lt;/em&gt; have long been favorites. Ross and Rachel are infuriatingly star-crossed in any language. But Mulva can only be Mulva in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt; &lt;ber&gt; &lt;/ber&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://jenniferkarmstrong.com/" target="new"&gt;Jennifer Keishin Armstrong&lt;/a&gt; is the author of &lt;/em&gt;Seinfeldia: The Secret World of the Show About Nothing That Changed Everything&lt;em&gt;, which will be published next year by Simon &amp; Schuster. She also wrote &lt;/em&gt;Mary and Lou and Rhoda and Ted: And all the Brilliant Minds Who Made The Mary Tyler Moore Show a Classic.&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="credit"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design by &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dylanlathrop"&gt;Dylan Lathrop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited by &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/mvzelenks"&gt;Michael Zelenko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/users/emilyyoshida?"&gt;Emily Yoshida&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="end" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yP7XevDJbjtb4d1m86uORu-J0qo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3816702/end.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/24/8809723/jerry-seinfeld-tv-show-international-translation"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/24/8809723/jerry-seinfeld-tv-show-international-translation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Keishin Armstrong</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-06-18T13:55:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-18T13:55:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Isle of Man TT: do racers dream of electric bikes?</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wcd-BCwxV7SoeM75PDQXqp423jo=/2x0:1016x676/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46565728/vs06-09_1436cxs.0.0.0.png" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;The Isle of Man is a strange and alien beast. Perhaps not on the surface, which is strewn with green fields dotted with grazing cows and picture-postcard cottages. But it plays host to a competition and a culture that are unlike those anywhere else in the world. If you live on or are visiting the Isle of Man, you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; a motorcycling enthusiast, and odds are pretty good that you also like danger, speed, and the intoxicating smell of gasoline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one-week Isle of Man Tourist Trophy (TT) event is regarded as the pinnacle of road racing for bike fanatics. A fast and varied course spanning most of the island provides a terrific challenge for both rider and bike, and every year — almost without exception — there are fatalities that underscore the perils of taking it on without the proper caution or training. It doesn't sound like a terribly welcoming place to be bringing experimental new technology to, but electric bikes have carved themselves a niche over the past few years and continue improving in their own category of zero-emissions racing, dubbed TT Zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script src="http://www.youtube.com/player_api"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3514112/noframework.waypoints.0.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3514114/inview.min.0.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="m-youtube_lede"&gt;
&lt;div id="upper_video" class="m-video-worms"&gt;
&lt;div class="m-video-worms__inner"&gt;
&lt;div id="player1" class="embed"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="text" class="text-wrap"&gt;
&lt;div class="text-wrap__inner"&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Do racers dream of electric bikes?&lt;span&gt;Silent motorcycles and their riders cheat death on the Isle of Man&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;span class="byline"&gt;By Vlad Savov&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Isle of Man&lt;/strong&gt; is a strange and alien beast. Perhaps not on the surface, which is strewn with green fields dotted with grazing cows and picture-postcard cottages. But it plays host to a competition and a culture that are unlike those anywhere else in the world. If you live on or are visiting the Isle of Man, you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; a motorcycling enthusiast, and odds are pretty good that you also like danger, speed, and the intoxicating smell of petrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;!--
var player1;
var player2;
function onYouTubePlayerAPIReady() {
    player1 = new YT.Player('player1', {
        playerVars: {
            'autoplay': 1,
            'controls': 0,
            'autohide': 1,
            'wmode': 'opaque',
            'showinfo': 0,
            'loop': 1,
            'mute': 1,
            'playlist': 'JGGqI5U1FRA'
        },
        videoId: 'JGGqI5U1FRA',
        events: {
            'onReady': onPlayerReady
        }
    });

    player2 = new YT.Player('player2', {
        playerVars: {
            'autoplay': 0,
            'controls': 0,
            'autohide': 1,
            'wmode': 'opaque',
            'showinfo': 0,
            'loop': 1,
            'mute': 1,
            'playlist': 'gWlPqIXInoY'
        },
        videoId: 'gWlPqIXInoY',
        events: {
            'onReady': onPlayerReady
        }
    });
}

function onPlayerReady(event) {
    event.target.mute();
    (function($) {
      $('#text').fadeIn(400);
    })(jQuery)
}

var inviewBottom = new Waypoint.Inview({
  element: $('#lower_video')[0],
  enter: function(direction) {
    player2.playVideo();
  },
  exited: function(direction) {
    player2.pauseVideo();
  }
})

$(window).scroll(function() {
  var hT = $('.m-video-worms').height(),
     wS = $(this).scrollTop();
  if (wS &gt; hT) {
    player1.pauseVideo();
  }
  else {
    player1.playVideo();
  }
});
// --&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one-week Isle of Man Tourist Trophy (TT) event is regarded as the pinnacle of road racing for bike fanatics. A fast and varied course spanning most of the island provides a terrific challenge for both rider and bike, and every year — almost without exception — there are fatalities that underscore the perils of taking it on without the proper caution or training. It doesn't sound like a terribly welcoming place to be bringing experimental new technology to, but electric bikes have carved themselves a niche over the past few years and continue improving in their own category of zero-emissions racing, dubbed TT Zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I found myself on the Isle of Man following the fortunes of the rookie Victory Racing team from the USA and its pair of &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/5/12/8589315/victory-electric-race-motorcycle-isle-of-man-tt"&gt;prototype electric bikes&lt;/a&gt;. Victory’s entry into the TT Zero class offered me a chance to learn about the current state of electric bike development and, along the way, discover the unique culture and global community that have built up around the Isle of Man and its iconic race series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-right"&gt; &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="victory racing" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R-1qIY5VbfcClhWPBvQwp8mxAVI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3803060/oo06-08_0758tt.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="victory racing" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tz8vsKK7zKOQ5_EmqcPXVFMiUrk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3803062/DSC02954.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="victory racing" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-4qBiD4dsUbQdeJrrxhYG7UO9Ds=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3803064/DSC02962.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victory came to market as a Harley-Davidson competitor when it was launched by snowmobile maker Polaris a decade and a half ago. Lithe, high-tech race bikes are about as far from Victory’s core two-wheeled competency as possible — but then these TT machines are actually the product of multiple years of development. At the start of this year, Polaris &lt;a target="new" href="http://blog.motorcycle.com/2015/01/15/motorcycle-news/polaris-acquires-electric-motorcycle-business-brammo/"&gt;acquired the motorcycle division of Oregon-based Brammo&lt;/a&gt;, whose all-electric Empulse forms the foundation for the present race bikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary Gray, Victory’s product chief, tells me the company has made "quite a few changes" in the brief period of time it’s had to work with Brammo’s assets, including the development of improved, structurally reinforced battery packs, new motor windings for better performance, and a reinforced frame to deal with the loads and strains of the rough TT track. Each bike weighs roughly 220kg (485lb) — not far off from the typical 200kg &lt;em&gt;dry&lt;/em&gt; weight of a gas-powered bike — and is designed to have just enough energy to complete the single-lap race and no more. The perfect run for one of these electric bikes will see it crossing the finish line with zero charge left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Our number one priority is safety," says a serious-looking Gray as he surveys his team of engineers making final preparations before the bikes’ first practice run. Each battery is fine-tuned so that it discharges at the same rate and small adjustments are made to the scant padding to tailor the bikes to the particular rider’s preferences. Gray isn’t alone in feeling trepidation about the 37-mile course ahead, which runs through towns, villages, and a treacherous mountain section that claims the lives of &lt;a target="new" href="http://www.iomtt.com/News/2015/June/03/Statement-issued-on-behalf-of-the-ACU.aspx"&gt;professional competitors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target="new" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-isle-of-man-33005546"&gt;amateur bikers&lt;/a&gt; each and every year. For a company looking to make its racing debut, Victory is showing great confidence by heading straight into the scariest and most challenging road race on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any other category, Victory’s inexperience would mark it out as a major underdog, however that’s not the case in the still-fledgling TT Zero class. There are only seven teams competing in the electric race, and three of them are composed of volunteers from UK universities — researchers who are combining their academic work with a passion for speed. Each battery-powered bike is built and engineered specifically for the TT and Victory is one of only three teams that were able to bring two electric vehicles to the Isle of Man, resulting in a total of 10 riders for the entire race. Compare that to the 71 competitors in the Sidecar race or the 91 in the Superbike class. Such a ragtag group of mostly amateur teams doesn’t immediately inspire great faith in the popularity and growth of electric racing, but it belies a recent history of superbly fast innovation and improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/18/8794819/isle-of-man-tt-2015-photo-essay"&gt;See next: Isle of Man TT photo essay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of the electric heap is Team Mugen, a Japanese outfit that’s entering its fourth TT Zero contest and is returning as the reigning champion. Best known as Honda’s semi-official performance tuner, Mugen is the brainchild of Hirotoshi Honda, the son of Honda founder Soichiro. It’s an independent company doing its own thing, though the motivation of its owner seems innately tied to the legacy of his father. Honda bikes have a grand history of excellent performances at the Isle of Man, and Mugen is building up a similar reputation for Hirotoshi in the electric races. Now 73, the Honda scion says that his company’s involvement in the TT Zero event is purely for the advancement of technology and the education of the young — and I fully believe him, given the lack of any immediate commercial or monetary benefit to competing in the race. Participating in TT Zero is about pride, speed, science, and little else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Winning the TT Zero earns you a wreath, a hat, and a place in history&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mugen’s progress is a perfect example of the steep trajectory of improvement in electric bikes: the company started competing in 2012 with an average speed around the TT track in the high 80s miles per hour, but by last year it was already speeding past an average of 117mph and this year set a new electric record with 119.3mph. Colin Whittamore, the UK General Manager for Mugen, puts it quite beautifully when he says "it’s a long way to go over the course of 80 minutes." Mugen only has four competitive races under its belt, each lasting roughly 20 minutes, and yet it’s accomplished a leap in performance that took gas-powered bikes a full 48 years to complete. The top bikes averaged 87mph in 1936 and didn’t surpass 117mph until 1984. "The gains to be found" with electric racing, says Whittamore, "are huge, and quite unusual for motorsport." To illustrate, he tells me that the original 2012 Mugen electric motor was twice as heavy as the current one and provided only 60 percent of the power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competitive field may be small and highly specialized, but the competitive quality of the electric bikes is no longer questioned. Five of the six bikes that completed the TT Zero run &lt;a target="new" href="http://www.iomtt.com/~/media/Files/2015/Race-results/SES-TT-Zero/Zero%20resulT.pdf"&gt;averaged in excess of 106mph&lt;/a&gt; — an unthinkable feat only a few years ago — and Victory’s debutant bikes weren’t too far off Mugen’s impeccable pace, achieving average speeds of 111.6mph and 109.7mph each. Mugen repeated its 2014 result by grabbing the first and second spots on the podium with both its riders breaking last year’s speed record and averaging in excess of 118mph. Victory claimed third and asserted itself as a significant player for future races to come. For a first performance, in a contest where just getting a battery-powered machine to complete the course is a feat in and of itself, Victory achieved its basic goals and then some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;&lt;iframe width="1020" height="574" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vlxZs2-gICc?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electric bikes are now within striking distance of the very best lap speeds around the TT track, which average just over 130mph in the hands of the most expert riders. And what’s more, those very same riders are enthusiastically embracing the new type of bike. Until recently, Bruce Anstey held the outright TT record with &lt;a target="new" href="http://www.iomtt.com/TT-Database/TT-Records/Lap-Records.aspx"&gt;132.3mph on his Honda superbike&lt;/a&gt;, but he also rides for Mugen in the TT Zero competition. His teammate and this year’s repeating TT Zero champion, John McGuinness took that gas-powered record from him this year with 132.7mph. McGuinness, despite some initial misgivings, is now one of the most ardent advocates of electric racing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I probably did snigger a little bit in the beginning," says McGuinness, "watching that first race in 2009 and seeing bikes with washing machine motors and car batteries strapped to them. But they’ve come a hell of a long way since then." Heading into this year’s Isle of Man series with 21 victories on the island, McGuinness is the most decorated living TT racer, and together with Anstey adds a great deal of credibility to the battery-powered race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;"Watching that first race in 2009 and seeing bikes with washing machine motors and car batteries strapped to them."&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But whether the mount is electric or gasoline, it’s hard to overstate just how dangerous and technical the Tourist Trophy is — even for established racers. The margin for error through some of the course’s most difficult sections is effectively zero, with even the smallest mistakes spelling disaster. William Dunlop, another established TT veteran with a spot on the top 10 speed list, was intended to lead the charge for Victory Racing before a crash in practice for the Superstock race ruled him out with a broken rib. He was replaced in the TT Zero competition by his Tyco BMW teammate Guy Martin, yet another racer with extensive TT experience, who finished fourth in the eventual race behind fellow Victory rider Lee Johnston. Johnston also picked up an injury ahead of the electric contest, but was able to carry on with a heavily bruised right shoulder and arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3803074/DSC03198.0.0.png"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, there were no crashes or calamities on the electric bikes, with the exception of one university team blowing out its battery in practice and thus forfeiting its spot in the race. Because the electric bikes are still unproven, no one is yet willing to push them to their limits, and that caution seems to be paying off with a safer contest. John McGuinness has even said that he probably could have surpassed the 120mph mark had he gone flat-out from the very beginning, but he started the bike in the less aggressive of its two modes, again prioritizing safety over absolute speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the present pace of innovation, by next year Mugen is almost certain to be riding past 120mph and Victory could be approaching today’s record. 2016 should also see the return of MotoCzysz to the Isle of Man. One of the true pioneers of electric racing, team owner Michael Czysz has been battling cancer in recent years, but he’s indicated his desire to get the team that dominated battery-powered TT racing before Mugen back into the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote lang="en" class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" lang="en"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MotoCzysz"&gt;@MotoCzysz&lt;/a&gt; great to hear from you and would be wonderful to see you here in 2016. We miss you here and best wishes from all at Team Mugen&lt;/p&gt;
— MUGENTT (@MUGENSHINDENTT) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MUGENSHINDENTT/status/608518033607413760"&gt;June 10, 2015&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the automotive industry, alternative powertrains are a long-term inevitability for the motorcycle business. Even Harley, the patron saint of two-wheeled chrome and noise, is crafting an electric strategy around its &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/24/5837642/riding-project-livewire-harley-davidson-first-electric-motorcycle"&gt;Project LiveWire&lt;/a&gt;. There may be no better proving ground for the technology than the 37 brutal miles of the TT course. Each team is contributing to the wider understanding of how to make electric motors more efficient, batteries more durable, and bike designs both more efficient &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; more durable. And none of them are doing it for any immediate profit. This is the biggest collection of friendly losers I’ve ever met, with each team committing significant investments of time and money into a race with a negligible prize fund and a track record of taking the lives of some of its biggest stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class="float-left"&gt; &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="isle of man tt" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f7zA23n6iJ5wIBVZ_XEjIyUxQA0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3803082/iom-tt-mugen.0.jpg"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;q&gt;The spectacle of speed matters as much as the speed&lt;/q&gt; &lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"One of the many reasons why you race is brand exposure," says Victory’s Gary Gray, "but we’re learning a lot here about what it takes to deliver electric performance reliably." His team isn’t selfish with those lessons, either, as I witnessed them helping engineers from the University of Nottingham’s TT Zero crew with parts and advice for putting together their bike for the upcoming race. This warmly collaborative approach may be merely a function of the wide gap in expected performance and might therefore fade away as competitiveness increases, but it’s still laudable and helps to advance research and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If speed is the only metric by which bike racing is to be judged, then battery-powered bikes have already proven their worth. But the fans that make the hallowed pilgrimage to the Isle of Man every year don’t come just for speed. They come for the spectacle of speed. That means thundering engine noise and a haze of exhaust fumes mixing with the waft of burnt rubber. "I think 100 percent that it’s the lack of noise that puts a lot of people off," says Mugen’s John McGuinness, in discussing why fan adoration hasn’t kept up with the rapid development of electric bikes. There’s an amusing dichotomy developing around battery power: the very things that the fans find off-putting and inauthentic, the lack of noise and smell, are the things that riders actually like. Victory’s Lee Johnston says he prefers the "peaceful" ride he gets on the electric bike, specifically calling out the roaring engine noise and gas fumes as downsides of conventional gas-powered bikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet full-image"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ugjGuqJLgwpM0zdd0w24OFNN7cU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3803084/vs06-10_1025cxs.0.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnston, McGuinness, Anstey, and most of the other riders appear comfortable and ready to embrace electric bikes as another, no less reputable form of two-wheeled racing in which they can compete. Some complain about the lack of power at the very top end, saying the bikes don’t allow for the same acceleration out of a corner and that "you’re on full throttle 80 percent of the time," but I’ve heard a lot more positive accounts of riding these bikes than negative ones. The rider’s job is simpler when you don’t have to be figuring out when and where to downshift, and the differences in skill become concentrated in how cleanly and efficiently each racer navigates the course. It looks to be the perfect diversifying race, offering a different test to the established bike classes. And yet, diversification seems like something the traditionalist Isle of Man audience will be reluctant to embrace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;"From a petrolhead's point of view, this is the only race left that's still pure. No safety, no bullshit."&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"From a petrolhead's point of view, this is the only race left that's still pure. No safety, no bullshit." This is the candid assessment of Miquel Gimeno-Fabra, a researcher on the University of Nottingham team, who’s quick to tell me that his views are not to be interpreted as those of his institution. He’s right, all the same. The Isle of Man attracts a peculiar class of ultra-committed fan that seeks to preserve what’s viewed as an endangered tradition of risky and thus spectacular road racing. Electric bikes might be fun to ride and all, but if they’re safe and quiet, what’s the point of running them around the TT track at all? Like skydiving or climbing Mount Everest, tells me Hirotoshi Honda, the risk is what makes things interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x60B0enAXMjSqTFBHp95eFCKJFw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3803070/vs06-10_1050cxs.0.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming to the Isle of Man&lt;/strong&gt; is a unique experience for any sports fan. Firstly, there’s the incredible commitment exhibited by everyone around you: &lt;a target="new" href="http://www.steam-packet.com/aboutus/news/2015/Jun/TT_2015"&gt;more than 14,000 motorcycles&lt;/a&gt; were ferried onto the island for this year’s TT series, all of them helmed by bikers in full racing gear. It’s not just dudes, either, as women are here in great number as well, riding their Suzukis and Kawasakis alongside male friends. One couple, David and Karen, got married at this year’s TT after coming to the show for 10 years in a row. The local Radio TT announced the happy news with the note that she was, in fact, wearing a dress at the wedding — a leather outfit might have been just as likely in this odd islandish realm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;It's like a Super Bowl where all the fans are wearing shoulder pads and helmets&lt;/q&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine attending the Super Bowl with a majority of the spectators wearing shoulder pads and helmets and you’ll get an inkling of how alien the Isle of Man can feel. That need not mean unwelcoming, however, as I was struck by how sociable everyone was — despite looking like spacemen and indulging in an occasionally reckless pursuit of high-speed thrills, these are probably the friendliest people I’ve met at any sporting event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TT race organizers contribute to the open atmosphere by providing an unprecedented level of access to the fans. You can stroll around the paddocks, observe the adjustments being made to each bike, and even walk up to your favorite rider and ask him for an autograph. When races are going on, the roads are closed down ahead of time, but people tend to crowd into the front yards of the houses adjoining the course and lean in to snap their own photos of the racers speeding by. It’s another risky habit on an island whose appeal seems inextricably linked to the atmosphere of ever-present danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="m-snippet"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ioqhtdF9UX1Zgo2jD7kYqiJ-dyE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3803092/vs06-10_1921cxs.0.0.png"&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="m-snippet thin"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My time on the Isle of Man has left me with some conflicting impressions. On the one hand, the TT track is the perfect proving ground for electric bikes as a credible racing class, one that could in due time compete with even the most powerful of superbikes. On the other hand, the Isle of Man series is revered for preserving a classic road racing heritage, and fans may never fully embrace the more modern variety of bike. The washing machine jokes persist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how people may feel about electric motors being part of the Isle of Man races, ultimately everyone agrees that they’ll play a hugely important role in all aspects of motor transportation. "It's just a matter of when. Electric vehicles, cars, bikes will be the future," says Mugen’s Whittamore. "We believe that electric is the future for all vehicle types," says Victory’s Gray. Neither of these companies has a road-going electric machine to sell — at least not yet — but both are accelerating development toward the future of which they speak with their participation in the TT Zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electric bike is growing up fast, and these are the people we have to thank for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="credit"&gt;
&lt;center&gt;* *&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photography by Vlad Savov&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead video footage provided by Victory Motorcycles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited by Chris Ziegler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/18/8794795/isle-of-man-tt-zero-victory-electric-motorcycle-race"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/6/18/8794795/isle-of-man-tt-zero-victory-electric-motorcycle-race</id>
    <author>
      <name>Vlad Savov</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
