<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Google Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/34086/verge-fv.png</icon>
  <updated>2015-08-08T08:00:01-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.theverge.com/google/rss/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/google" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-08T08:00:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-08T08:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google's Project Fi cell phone service is simple, until it's not</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tvPELMZCPINnhzXi001D-c86sCY=/5x0:2037x1355/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46920250/verge-2015-08-07_11-12-03.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/4/22/8471469/google-fi-all-the-news-on-the-search-giants-plan-to-remake-the"&gt;Google's Project Fi&lt;/a&gt;, if you don't recall, is the innovative new cell phone service that combines Wi-Fi calling, service that works on either Sprint or T-Mobile's network (whichever is faster), and a cheap and nicely predictable pricing plan that starts at $20 for voice and text and costs $10 per gig of data. It also only works on the Nexus 6. I just got mine set up yesterday, and I'm pleased with it so far, though there are complications I'm still trying to wrap my head around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that Fi is essentially sharing infrastructure with the soon-to-be-unceremoniously-destroyed-in-a-spring-cleaning product known as Google Voice. Google has been slowly but surely deprecating Voice by moving most of its features into Hangouts (and,...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/8/9118283/googles-project-fi-cell-phone-service-is-simple-until-its-not"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/8/9118283/googles-project-fi-cell-phone-service-is-simple-until-its-not"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/8/9118283/googles-project-fi-cell-phone-service-is-simple-until-its-not</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-07T10:49:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-07T10:49:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Maps for iOS now has a night mode</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AaH45v_4I0qb1GIjjkY1Ul2SpxU=/0x0:2000x1333/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46917038/v-DSC09935-12.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;There aren't many areas where Apple Maps has an edge over Google Maps, but one of them has been the inclusion of a night mode with darker graphics that are easier to read after sunset. As of yesterday, that advantage is gone. Google Maps has added a night mode to its iOS app, making the app automatically switch to a darker color palette when giving directions at night. It's a small but handy update that should make Google Maps more useable for people with iPhones. As for people on Android, they've had a night mode in Google Maps for years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/7/9115887/google-maps-night-mode-ios"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/7/9115887/google-maps-night-mode-ios"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/7/9115887/google-maps-night-mode-ios</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-06T13:00:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-06T13:00:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Translator is a must-have app for your smartwatch</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iMIR5ZMuvChhoJp28TihRSbc1Ck=/2x0:1016x676/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46910478/microsofttranslatorios1_1020.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;Smartwatch apps haven't really blown us away so far, but Microsoft has just delivered one that's certain to be incredibly useful, even if it's not earth-shattering. Today the company launched Microsoft Translator for iOS and Android, with both versions also including apps for their respective smartwatch platforms. So if you've got an Apple Watch or, say, a Moto 360, you'll be able to get instant translations in 50 languages without ever having to pull out your smartphone. This could be hugely valuable if you're traveling somewhere unfamiliar or taking a getaway vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the phone, Translator has a super simple layout — by design — so that it's easy to just show someone your screen and give them a sense of what you're looking for or...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9110269/microsoft-translator-app-apple-watch-android-wear"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9110269/microsoft-translator-app-apple-watch-android-wear"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9110269/microsoft-translator-app-apple-watch-android-wear</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-06T09:33:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-06T09:33:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Moto G (2015) review: this is Motorola's real flagship</title>
    <content type="html">
  		 &lt;p&gt;When Motorola introduced its latest series of smartphones last week, all eyes were on the Moto X. For several years, the Moto X has been Motorola's top-of-the-line phone — the one we all look to when divining Motorola's fortunes. But Motorola made it clear that its fortune is now tied up in something far more unassuming: the Moto G, which in just over a year and a half has become "Motorola's most successful smartphone ever."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still less than two years after its initial launch, the Moto G is getting its third overhaul. Motorola already has a working formula, and this year, it's polishing off the rough spots. Specifically, Motorola is addressing the G’s design, camera quality, and data speeds. It's once again trying to wow people with how...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9102119/moto-g-review-2015-video"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9102119/moto-g-review-2015-video"/>
    <link rel="enclosure" type="video/mp4" href="http://www.theverge.com/rss/redirect.mp4?url=http://ak.c.ooyala.com/h5YmVwdjqGfh3KQC6Y3Voxnue2dn_5Jd/DOcJ-FxaFrRg4gtDEwOjFpaDowODE7jj"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9102119/moto-g-review-2015-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-06T02:30:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-06T02:30:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here's why LG is still making flip phones</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oeywzxSZ-wFj3NzmQY4mKajkYG4=/0x0:1200x800/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46907428/lg-flip-wine-smart.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;Like AOL subscriptions, the flip phone seems to be an anachronism, a leftover fragment from another age. And yet, just like AOL subscriptions, the flip phone persists, with LG this week introducing its &lt;a href="http://www.lgnewsroom.com/2015/08/new-lg-wine-smart-delivers-smartphone-features-with-familiar-folder-style-convenience/"&gt;Wine Smart&lt;/a&gt; handset. It runs Android on a 3.2-inch screen, comes in a choice of burgundy or navy, and it even has an LTE connection. Plus it has a physical number pad and a bunch of shortcut buttons that old Nokia might have been proud of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be easy to poke fun at something we don't understand, but it's far more interesting to find out &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; this LG Wine Smart handset (and a number of similar ones from Samsung) still exists. So I asked. Here's what LG told me: flip phones remain popular with four, somewhat related classes of users....&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9107011/lg-wine-smart-flip-phone-android"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9107011/lg-wine-smart-flip-phone-android"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/6/9107011/lg-wine-smart-flip-phone-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Vlad Savov</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-05T19:06:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-05T19:06:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dreamify will make it easier than ever to turn your favorite pictures horrifying</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K0eiAKSZClXCjX-c7snMnTwophQ=/0x0:804x536/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46905454/dogknight_3346130k.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;Google's Deep Dream software &lt;a href="http://googleresearch.blogspot.ca/2015/07/deepdream-code-example-for-visualizing.html"&gt;was created to help&lt;/a&gt; the company's engineers understand artificial neural networks, but its development yielded unintended results. Computers were fed millions of mundane images — dogs, families, nature, whatever you like — as a means of learning our world's organic visual language, but the process had side effects. It turns out that machines see our lives in a completely different way. To them, we're living in a universe that's unsettling, alien, and weirdly compelling by human standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the code propelling Deep Dream was made available to the public, it became hard to go a day or two without seeing a friend or a &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/7/8904641/fear-and-loathing-clip-google-deep-dream-visualization"&gt;famous movie scene distorted&lt;/a&gt; through the code's application. People can't resist turning...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9104121/dreamify-app-google-deep-dream-ios-android"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9104121/dreamify-app-google-deep-dream-ios-android"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9104121/dreamify-app-google-deep-dream-ios-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jamieson Cox</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-05T14:33:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-05T14:33:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the Stagefright bug changed Android security</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a6n95gNUXxUENjlSOEF9Mis54gA=/2x0:1016x676/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46900008/android-doll-stock-robot_1020.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;It's been 10 days since Zimperium's Joshua Drake &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/27/9045841/android-vulnerability-mms-stagefright-exploit-hack"&gt;revealed a new Android vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; called Stagefright — and Android is just starting to recover. The bug allows an attacker to remotely execute code through a phony multimedia text message, in many cases without the user even seeing the message itself. Google has had months to write a patch and already had one ready when the bug was announced, but as expected, getting the patch through manufacturers and carriers was complicated and difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, something unexpected happened: the much-maligned Android update system started to work. Samsung, HTC, LG, Sony and Android One have already announced pending patches for the bug, along with a device-specific patch for the Alcatel Idol 3. &lt;a style="background-color: #ffffff;" href="http://global.samsungtomorrow.com/samsung-announces-an-android-security-update-process-to-ensure-timely-protection-from-security-vulnerabilities/"&gt;I...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9099627/google-stagefright-android-vulnerability-protect-patch"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9099627/google-stagefright-android-vulnerability-protect-patch"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9099627/google-stagefright-android-vulnerability-protect-patch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-05T14:25:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-05T14:25:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Fiber's next city is its biggest yet: San Antonio, Texas</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ot4IpUgrj59Zla91pdj5Dfm7bzg=/0x0:2039x1359/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46902042/fiber12_2040.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;Google Fiber is coming to San Antonio, a move that will make the company's speedy 1Gbps internet available to the city's 1.4 million residents. So far this is the largest market that Google is launching Fiber in, though not the first in Texas — service in Austin &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/12/1/7314335/google-fiber-begins-austin-signups"&gt;started up last December&lt;/a&gt;. San Antonio's people are in for a tough wait; Google is only now nearing the design phase of a daunting project that calls for over 4,000 miles of fiber-optic cable. With San Antonio's addition, here's what the current Fiber map looks like — now and for the near future. In March, San Antonio city officials worked to &lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/03/14/san-antonio-approves-google-fiber-lease/" target="_blank"&gt;clear the way for Google to enter town&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
    


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So San Antonio has graduated from "potential Fiber city" into the real thing. But as...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9101195/google-fiber-san-antonio-announced"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9101195/google-fiber-san-antonio-announced"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9101195/google-fiber-san-antonio-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-05T13:38:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-05T13:38:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube videos will no longer get stuck at 301+ views</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i-ZKwnbj7VB8nRXrfs5WipEuKDA=/0x0:1999x1333/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46902084/v-DSC08852-1.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;YouTube videos' view counter famously gets stuck at "301+" views, but that beautifully ambiguous state is going away forever. YouTube announced this morning that it's doing away with 301+ and will start to keep video views more up to date. It's long frozen the counter after 301 so that it can take some time to filter out any fake views from robots, but doing so has meant keeping the counter really imprecise while thousands of legitimate views come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube says that it'll now continue to add new views as they happen, as long as it's sure that they're genuine; views that YouTube suspects as coming from bots will be added later if they're cleared. This should help video creators get a better perception of how their video is doing early...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9100759/youtube-301-view-count-freeze-going-away"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9100759/youtube-301-view-count-freeze-going-away"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9100759/youtube-301-view-count-freeze-going-away</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2015-08-05T10:31:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-05T10:31:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>This is what Android looks like in 2015</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QaPWGyVKchqB49dbD--UajwEpQs=/0x0:2039x1359/800x536/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/46900452/android1_2040.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  		 &lt;p&gt;Inherent to Android is a world of phones and tablets in different sizes, using different technology, and with different features and sensors. While that's led to fragmentation issues that can make life harder for developers, it's also led to a wealth of interesting hardware, with manufacturers competing to be the best at both budget and premium prices. Over the past several years, that landscape has continued to shift. Sure, Samsung may still be the biggest name around, but there are now a huge number of small manufacturers that have thrown their hats in the ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the fourth year in a row, OpenSignal, which makes an app that maps wireless signal coverage, has &lt;a href="http://opensignal.com/reports/2015/08/android-fragmentation/"&gt;mapped out the state of Android&lt;/a&gt; to show what that immense world of phones,...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9099695/android-fragmentation-report-2015-opensignal"&gt;Continue reading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9099695/android-fragmentation-report-2015-opensignal"/>
    <id>http://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9099695/android-fragmentation-report-2015-opensignal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
